<main>
<word>
	<name>bias</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>bias</title>
		<eng-def>
			a situation in which you support or oppose someone or something in an unfair way because you are influenced by your personal opinions
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>önyargý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bias towards/against private education</ex>
			<ex>
				The news channel has been accused of bias in favour of the government.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>His natural bias was to respect things as they were.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This document provides guidance on the stages in scheme development at which optimism bias can be reduced.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The townspeople show a bias in favour of French habits and fashions.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To illustrate the self-serving bias with regard to success, I will draw on my own experiences.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His natural parts were excellent; and a strong bias in the direction of abstract thought, and mathematics in particular, was noticeable at an early date.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This bias is reflected in the maxim that "correction should precede interpretation," which is no more than a half-truth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It gives copious details, and, as he had access to the correspondence and official documents of the Spanish leaders, it is, although necessarily possessing bias, the fullest and most authentic record existing of the events it relates.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sovereign as compared with her ministers has, because she is the sovereign, the advantage of long experience, wide survey, elevated position and entire disconnexion from the bias of party.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its author, with a considerable mathematical and mechanical bias, reckoned entirely with the quantity, not with the quality of his units, and relied almost implicitly upon his formulae.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			That phrase accurately describes the prevalent bias of its author's mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Lotze was a man of considerable attainments in special science; perhaps he reveals here the bias of the scientific mind, and possibly even its limitations.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He adhered henceforth to the army party, but with a constant bias in favour of the king.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Another side is the recurring exhibition of the fact that these witnesses were persecuted only by those whose action should create no bias against the persecuted.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The cause of medical materialism is the natural bias of physicians towards explaining the health and disease of mind by the health and disease of body.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But the Christian bias is sure to make theologians, who borrow a doctrine of the Absolute, interpret it in a Christian sense; hence we may consider it something of an accident that even an Augustine fails exactly to put the argument in form.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			All that Hauch wrote is marked by great qualities, and by distinction; he had a native bias towards the mystical, which, however, he learned to keep in abeyance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bias of modern practice, in short, is towards milder methods, not only in treatment, but in those anticipatory processes which may render imprisonment unnecessary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Despite the almost inevitable US bias, it is still worth a visit.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			One of them seeing Bias without anything, advised him to follow the example of the rest.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>codon bias.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>prejudice</definition>
		<definition>slant</definition>
		<definition>influence</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>leaning</syn>
			<syn>bent</syn>
			<syn>tendency</syn>
			<syn>inclination</syn>
			<syn>penchant</syn>
			<syn>intolerance</syn>
			<syn>bigotry</syn>
			<syn>propensity</syn>
			<syn>favouritism</syn>
			<syn>predisposition</syn>
			<syn>nepotism</syn>
			<syn>unfairness</syn>
			<syn>predilection</syn>
			<syn>proclivity</syn>
			<syn>partiality</syn>
			<syn>narrow-mindedness</syn>
			<syn>proneness</syn>
			<syn>one-sidedness</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>cross</syn>
			<syn>angle</syn>
			<syn>diagonal line</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>influence</syn>
			<syn>colour</syn>
			<syn>weight</syn>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>distort</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>warp</syn>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>predispose</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>equity</ant>
			<ant>equality</ant>
			<ant>fairness</ant>
			<ant>neutrality</ant>
			<ant>objectivity</ant>
			<ant>impartiality</ant>
			<ant>open-mindedness</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>acquiesce</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>acquiesce</title>
		<eng-def>to agree to something, often when you do not want to</eng-def>
		<tr-def>kabullenmek, istemeden razï¿½ olmak, ses ï¿½ï¿½karmamak</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>He will acquiesce simply because he is a sick man.</sentence>
		<sentence>Will they acquiesce in that sorry state of affairs?</sentence>
		<sentence>Do you think they acquiesce in the precedent they will soon set?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The committee will acquiesce in any decision on which it is not fully informed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>But surely serious thought cannot acquiesce in a dual control.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even the few who were patriotic enough to acquiesce in the change by no means liked it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Victims would not acquiesce in any sham process aimed at facilitating an amnesty for the terrorists who have escaped justice.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			A broken-hearted man, Charles was compelled to acquiesce in retreat.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The hellenizers had not lost all hope of converting the nation and were indisposed to acquiesce in the concordat.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			By this device the Lords were obliged to acquiesce in the repeal of the paper-duty.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Hormizds son, Chosroes II., was set up against his father and forced to acquiesce in his execution.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Throughout this dual existence Mr. Dodgson pertinaciously refused to acquiesce in being publicly identified with "Lewis Carroll."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The result was the defeat of the Lancastrians at St Albans, and for a year Margaret had to acquiesce in York's power.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He was fond of field sports and seemed to acquiesce in his mother's occupation of power and in the rule of her favourites.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The proud Arabic lords could not acquiesce in paying to a plebeian...
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Christian theology cannot acquiesce in this.</sentence>
		<sentence>Douglas urged the South to acquiesce in Lincoln's election.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The warmth of his muscular chest under the soft knit of his shirt, and the strength in the arms that gently coaxed her close again, tempted her to acquiesce.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			those of Bohemia, Moravia, Carinthia and Tirol, which were already pledged to support the January policy of the government, did not acquiesce in the February policy; and they refused to elect except on terms which the government could not accept.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			They had undermined the foundations of scientific certainty, and so far as the fecundity of contemporary science did not give them pause, were ready, notwithstanding the difference of their starting-point, to acquiesce in the formula as well as the temper of Pyrrhonism.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>submit</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>submit</syn>
			<syn>allow</syn>
			<syn>agree</syn>
			<syn>accept</syn>
			<syn>approve</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>bend</syn>
			<syn>surrender</syn>
			<syn>consent</syn>
			<syn>tolerate</syn>
			<syn>comply</syn>
			<syn>give in</syn>
			<syn>conform</syn>
			<syn>succumb</syn>
			<syn>go along with</syn>
			<syn>cave in</syn>
			<syn>concur</syn>
			<syn>assent</syn>
			<syn>capitulate</syn>
			<syn>accede</syn>
			<syn>play ball</syn>
			<syn>toe the line</syn>
			<syn>bow to</syn>
			<syn>hoist the white flag</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>fight</ant>
			<ant>resist</ant>
			<ant>disagree</ant>
			<ant>veto</ant>
			<ant>dissent</ant>
			<ant></ant>
			<ant>demur</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bribe</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>bribe</title>
		<eng-def>
			money or a gift given to someone so that they will do something for you, usually something dishonest
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>rüþvet verme</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>The politician was accused of accepting bribes from businessmen.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>The world could not bribe him.</sentence>
		<sentence>I thought we could try to bribe Skippy with them.</sentence>
		<sentence>money was to be obtained in order to bribe the German electors.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			26) to bribe the king of Damascus to renounce his league with Baasha and attack Israel.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			a bribe for the high-priesthood and another for leave and to convert Jerusalem into a Greek city (2 Macc. iv.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even worse - she'd lost the bribe she brought for the Oceanan messenger.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			These payments, the cynics would argue, bribe the poor to back the system.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The new prince, who was compelled to purchase his elevation with a heavy bribe, proceeded to the country which he was selected to govern, and of the language of which he was in nearly every case totally ignorant, accompanied by a horde of needy hangers-on; he and his acolytes counted on recouping themselves in as short a time as possible for their initial outlay and in laying by a sufficiency to live on after the termination of the prince's brief authority.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In 776 Mandi constrained him for a large bribe to renounce his right of succession in favour of his sons, Musa and Harun.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			When, owing to the numerous cases of treachery among the princes, the choice became limited to a few families the plan was hit upon of frequently shifting the prince from one province to the other: the prince of Wallachia, the richer of the two principalities, was always ready to pay a handsome douceur to avert his transfer to Yassy; the prince of Moldavia was equally ready to bribe his supporters at Constantinople to secure his appointment to Wallachia.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She hadn't thought to use it as a bribe; if it were gold, it might be worth something.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The secretary y had already accepted a bribe, but Swift was informed that he might still have the place for 100o.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Another frequent subject of complaint was found in certain sacred vessels which the bishop of Sirmium had sent as a bribe to the secretary of Attila, and which had been by him, fraudulently, as his master contended, pawned to a silversmith at Rome.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			All attempts to bribe him were unsuccessful, and Pyrrhus is said to have been so impressed that he released the prisoners without ransom (Plutarch, Pyrrhus, 18).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			a bribe, and hastened to reconquer Euboea; but the other land possessions could not be recovered, and in a thirty years' truce which was arranged in 445 Athens definitely renounced her predominance in Greece Proper.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He first thought of becoming a minister at a very early date, if we may believe a story contained in the Memoires of the duchesse d'Abrantes, to the effect that in May 1789 the queen tried to bribe him, but that he refused this and expressed his wish to be a minister.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			A more unpleasant side to the question is that he gave the king a safe conduct, which was afterwards seen by Sir Donald Stewart, before he left the palace, and presumably for a bribe; and he took an armlet and rings from the bodies of the princes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To them Alexius, son of the deposed Isaac, made appeal, promising as a crowning bribe to heal the schism of East and West if they would help him to depose his uncle.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In April 1695 he was impeached once more by the Commons for having received a bribe of 5000 guineas to procure the new charter for the East India Company.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Given that she had no money or belongings that might possibly be of interest to the people of this planet, how could she bribe or pay someone to take her home?
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>inducement</definition>
		<definition>buy off</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>inducement</syn>
			<syn>incentive</syn>
			<syn>pay-off</syn>
			<syn>graft</syn>
			<syn>sweetener</syn>
			<syn>kickback</syn>
			<syn>sop</syn>
			<syn>backhander</syn>
			<syn>enticement</syn>
			<syn>hush money</syn>
			<syn>payola</syn>
			<syn>allurement</syn>
			<syn>corrupting gift</syn>
			<syn>reward for treachery</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>buy off</syn>
			<syn>reward</syn>
			<syn>pay off</syn>
			<syn>lure</syn>
			<syn>corrupt</syn>
			<syn>get at</syn>
			<syn>square</syn>
			<syn>suborn</syn>
			<syn>grease the palm or hand of</syn>
			<syn>oil the palm of</syn>
			<syn>influence by gifts</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>basis</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>on a daily/monthly/regular, etc basis</title>
		<eng-def>how often something happens or is done</eng-def>
		<tr-def>günlük/aylýk/düzenli olarak, aralýklarla</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Meetings are held on a weekly basis.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>on a commercial/full-time/percentage, etc basis</title>
		<eng-def>the way something happens or is organized</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			ticari/tam zamanlý/yüzde vs. esasýna dayalý olarak, þeklinde, biçiminde
		</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>We will consider claims for asylum on a case by case basis.</ex>
			<ex>We deal with each case on an individual basis.</ex>
			<ex>She's having private lessons on a one-to-one basis.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>basis</title>
		<eng-def>the reason for something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>dayanak, bir þeyin dayandýðý nokta</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Marks are awarded on the basis of progress and performance.</ex>
			<ex>There is no legal basis for his claim.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>basis</title>
		<eng-def>a situation, fact, or idea from which something can develop</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir gerçek veya fikrin çýkýþ noktasý, durumu</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Dani's essay can serve as a basis for our discussion.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>So you're on a first name basis with him, huh?</sentence>
		<sentence>It wasn't as if there was any basis for the feeling.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I remembered a judge had tossed out a search warrant obtained only on the basis of our tip.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>In 1840 we have the first safe basis for comparison of strength.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The French census uses the commune as the basis of its returns, and employs the following classifications in respect to communal population: (I) Total communal population.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			No doubt because she didn't have to do it on a regular basis as Alex did.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Was that Shipton's basis for everything?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			in his Encyclical of August 4, 1879, which directed the clergy to take the teachings of Aquinas as the basis of their theological position.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>This is the basis of real intercourse.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Now, on a regular basis, videos appear which bring to life something that would otherwise be merely an ill-formed image in our minds.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Department personnel operated on the basis of out-of-sight, out-of-mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even the Chinese philosopher was wise enough to regard the individual as the basis of the empire.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What if you could do agriculture perfectly on a per-grape basis, each grape getting individual attention?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The following tables, showing the growth of the largest towns in France, are drawn up on the basis of the fourth classification, which is used throughout this work in the articles on French towns, except where otherwise stated.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			trans., from 2nd German ed., The Philosophy of Religion on the Basis of its History, 4 vols., 1886-1888).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			With calm courage he returned to his poverty and his favourite studies, and in 1725 published the first edition of the work that forms the basis of his renown, Principii d'una scienza nuova.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In July 1865, when politics had shifted from the basis of the 1861 Constitution, he laid down office, and retired from public affairs.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			- Although the legal basis for the final stage is found in the legislation of the time of Moses (latter part of the second millennium B.C.), it is in reality scarcely earlier than the 5th century B.C., and the Jewish theory finds analogies when developments of the Levitical service are referred to David (I Chron.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Still, a case that spawned a novel basis for argument was always a welcomed diversion from their increasing caseload.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It couldn't have been better, but entertaining three men on a daily basis was a mental workout.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>arrangement</definition>
		<definition>foundation</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>arrangement</syn>
			<syn>way</syn>
			<syn>system</syn>
			<syn>footing</syn>
			<syn>agreement</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>foundation</syn>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>base</syn>
			<syn>ground</syn>
			<syn>footing</syn>
			<syn>theory</syn>
			<syn>bottom</syn>
			<syn>principle</syn>
			<syn>premise</syn>
			<syn>starting point</syn>
			<syn>groundwork</syn>
			<syn>point of departure</syn>
			<syn>principal element</syn>
			<syn>chief ingredient</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>ally</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>ally</title>
		<eng-def>
			someone who supports you, especially when other people are against you
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>müttefik, destekleyen, arka çýkan, ortak</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>ally</title>
		<eng-def>
			a country that has agreed to help another country, especially in a war
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			savaþ müttefiki ülke, müttefik, dost, ortak amaçlarý olan ülkeler
		</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>"I am not your ally," he repeated.</sentence>
		<sentence>You're my only true ally of any influence with the Council.</sentence>
		<sentence>The odd little man was the loyal ally A'Ran considered him!</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Germany, an ally of Austria-Hungary, was obligated by treaty to defend it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Our new friend may be an ally to Sirian.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I know this ally and arranged for her travel without Sirian's knowledge.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Here may be noticed three genera of large extinct marsupials from the Pleistocene of Australia whose affinities appear to ally them to the wombat-group on the one hand and to the phalangers on the other.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There is no negotiating with the Yirkin scum or my father's killer, A'Ran thought but held his tongue, aware his only ally believed himself right in this.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In 1896 and 1900 he voted the Republican ticket, but did not ally himself with the organization.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His gaze darkened, and Xander knew his long-time ally was thinking of their shared history from the time before the Schism that split the mortal and immortal worlds apart.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"The northern is our most likely avenue, more so because we have an ally in the mountains," Hilden replied.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Those she sent north to our ally, Dierdirien.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			to the papacy in 1159 added a powerful ally to the republican party.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			A'Ran forced his attention away, certain that this ally was as true as any despite his haste in addressing nishani.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Jetr, the only Council member he trusted, had been an ally for three generations of his family without appearing to age.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Kiki shook his head and stalked off into the brush. Kris held out his hand to Hannah, unable to shake the small part of him that was grateful he had one ally, even if she shouldn't have come.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Testing his magic, he realized he could call forth a portal. He needed an ally, but it wasn't Kris. He had no intention of bringing Kris to meet Darkyn, not when he didn't know what Darkyn wanted. His thoughts went to Gabriel, the best friend he hoped he hadn't lost completely. Gabe wouldn't try to negotiate with Darkyn if things went bad.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Their king was insane and they changed him for another-- Bernadotte, who promptly went mad--for no Swede would ally himself with Russia unless he were mad.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The conquest was easy; but, when it came to a partition, Ferdinand played his ally false.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			With his mercenaries behind him he met with some small successes in his fight for Normandy, but on the 27th of July he and his ally, the emperor Otto IV., met with a crushing defeat at Bouvines at the hands of Philip Augustus, and even the king himself was compelled to recognise that his hopes of recovering Normandy were at an end.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>partner</definition>
		<definition>combine</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>partner</syn>
			<syn>friend</syn>
			<syn>colleague</syn>
			<syn>associate</syn>
			<syn>mate</syn>
			<syn>blood or blud</syn>
			<syn>accessory</syn>
			<syn>comrade</syn>
			<syn>helper</syn>
			<syn>collaborator</syn>
			<syn>accomplice</syn>
			<syn>confederate</syn>
			<syn>co-worker</syn>
			<syn>main man</syn>
			<syn>bedfellow</syn>
			<syn>cobber</syn>
			<syn>coadjutor</syn>
			<syn>E hoa</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>combine</syn>
			<syn>unite</syn>
			<syn>join</syn>
			<syn>link</syn>
			<syn>marry</syn>
			<syn>mix</syn>
			<syn>bond</syn>
			<syn>associate</syn>
			<syn>pool</syn>
			<syn>bind</syn>
			<syn>connect</syn>
			<syn>compound</syn>
			<syn>blend</syn>
			<syn>integrate</syn>
			<syn>merge</syn>
			<syn>put together</syn>
			<syn>unify</syn>
			<syn>fuse</syn>
			<syn>synthesize</syn>
			<syn>band together</syn>
			<syn>meld</syn>
			<syn>join together</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>rival</ant>
			<ant>enemy</ant>
			<ant>opponent</ant>
			<ant>competitor</ant>
			<ant>foe</ant>
			<ant>adversary</ant>
			<ant>antagonist</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>divide</ant>
			<ant>alienate</ant>
			<ant>disunite</ant>
			<ant></ant>
			<ant>disaffect</ant>
			<ant></ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>abstract</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>relating to ideas and not real things</eng-def>
		<tr-def>soyut</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an abstract concept</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>
			Abstract art involves shapes and colours and not images of real things or people.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			gerçek nesne ve kiþilerin imgelerinden çok renk ve þekilleri içeren soyut sanat
		</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			They had no abstract ideas; in their minds all was concrete, visible and tangible.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>His abstract submission met the deadline.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Choose five abstract nouns relating to recent conversational themes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Do you have an abstract of a paper or presentation you would like to give?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He presented abstract concepts with empirical data.</sentence>
		<sentence>Can I have an abstract of the article?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Thus Descartes gave to modern geometry that abstract and general character in which consists its superiority to the geometry of the ancients.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He was searching for an abstract expressionist painting by de Kooning.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Congress (London, 18 95), p. 735 (English Abstract, p. 748).</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It does not appear, however, that a regularly organized or numerous Orphic sect ever existed, nor that Orphism ever became popular; it was too abstract, too full of symbolism.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He asked me how I had taught Helen adjectives and the names of abstract ideas like goodness and happiness.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What remains to be done is, not to explain how such a world manages to be what it is, nor how we came to form these notions, but merely this - to expel from the circle and totality of our conceptions those abstract notions which are inconsistent and jarring, or to remodel and define them so that they may constitute a consistent and harmonious view.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Moreover, the abstract terms stem, leaf, root, &c., are absolutely indispensable; and are continually used in this sense by the most ardent organographers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Abstract expressionism was a New York painting movement of the 1940's with its artistic roots based upon abstract art.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Secondly: from the discrepancy between the pure abstract law of self-consistent reason and the pleasuretinged nature of man, we infer or postulate Immortality.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was evident that Prince Andrew was not interested in such abstract conversation.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the very nature of things, articulation is an unsatisfactory means of education; while the use of the manual alphabet quickens and invigorates mental activity, since through it the deaf child is brought into close contact with the English language, and the highest and most abstract ideas may be conveyed to the mind readily and accurately.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The neuter term brahma is used in the Rigveda both in the abstract sense of "devotion, worship," and in the concrete sense of "devotional rite, prayer, hymn."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The first, De Sancta Trinitate, is addressed to Symmachus (Domino Patri Symmacho), and the result of the short discussion, which is of an abstract nature, and deals partly with the ten categories, is that unity is predicated absolutely, or, in regard to the substance of the Deity, trinity is predicated relatively.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Klebs, Guide to Exhibit of the German Amber Industry at World's Fair (St Louis, 1904); and abstract by G.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>theoretical</definition>
		<definition>symbolic</definition>
		<definition>summary</definition>
		<definition>extract</definition>
		<definition>summarize</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>theoretical</syn>
			<syn>general</syn>
			<syn>academic</syn>
			<syn>intellectual</syn>
			<syn>subtle</syn>
			<syn>profound</syn>
			<syn>philosophical</syn>
			<syn>speculative</syn>
			<syn>unrealistic</syn>
			<syn>conceptual</syn>
			<syn>indefinite</syn>
			<syn>deep</syn>
			<syn>occult</syn>
			<syn>hypothetical</syn>
			<syn>generalized</syn>
			<syn>impractical</syn>
			<syn>arcane</syn>
			<syn>notional</syn>
			<syn>abstruse</syn>
			<syn>recondite</syn>
			<syn>theoretic</syn>
			<syn>conjectural</syn>
			<syn>unpractical</syn>
			<syn>nonconcrete</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>symbolic</syn>
			<syn>figurative</syn>
			<syn>emblematic</syn>
			<syn>impressionistic</syn>
			<syn>non-representational</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summary</syn>
			<syn>résumé</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>essence</syn>
			<syn>summing-up</syn>
			<syn>digest</syn>
			<syn>epitome</syn>
			<syn>rundown</syn>
			<syn>condensation</syn>
			<syn>compendium</syn>
			<syn>synopsis</syn>
			<syn>précis</syn>
			<syn>recapitulation</syn>
			<syn>review</syn>
			<syn>abridgment</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>draw</syn>
			<syn>pull</syn>
			<syn>remove</syn>
			<syn>separate</syn>
			<syn>withdraw</syn>
			<syn>isolate</syn>
			<syn>pull out</syn>
			<syn>take out</syn>
			<syn>take away</syn>
			<syn>detach</syn>
			<syn>dissociate</syn>
			<syn>pluck out</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summarize</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>shorten</syn>
			<syn>condense</syn>
			<syn>abbreviate</syn>
			<syn>epitomize</syn>
			<syn>abridge</syn>
			<syn>précis</syn>
			<syn>synopsize</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>real</ant>
			<ant>material</ant>
			<ant>specific</ant>
			<ant>actual</ant>
			<ant>concrete</ant>
			<ant>definite</ant>
			<ant>factual</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>expansion</ant>
			<ant>enlargement</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>add</ant>
			<ant>inject</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bias</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>bias</title>
		<eng-def>
			a situation in which you support or oppose someone or something in an unfair way because you are influenced by your personal opinions
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>önyargý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bias towards/against private education</ex>
			<ex>
				The news channel has been accused of bias in favour of the government.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>His natural bias was to respect things as they were.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This document provides guidance on the stages in scheme development at which optimism bias can be reduced.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The townspeople show a bias in favour of French habits and fashions.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To illustrate the self-serving bias with regard to success, I will draw on my own experiences.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His natural parts were excellent; and a strong bias in the direction of abstract thought, and mathematics in particular, was noticeable at an early date.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This bias is reflected in the maxim that "correction should precede interpretation," which is no more than a half-truth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It gives copious details, and, as he had access to the correspondence and official documents of the Spanish leaders, it is, although necessarily possessing bias, the fullest and most authentic record existing of the events it relates.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sovereign as compared with her ministers has, because she is the sovereign, the advantage of long experience, wide survey, elevated position and entire disconnexion from the bias of party.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its author, with a considerable mathematical and mechanical bias, reckoned entirely with the quantity, not with the quality of his units, and relied almost implicitly upon his formulae.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			That phrase accurately describes the prevalent bias of its author's mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Lotze was a man of considerable attainments in special science; perhaps he reveals here the bias of the scientific mind, and possibly even its limitations.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He adhered henceforth to the army party, but with a constant bias in favour of the king.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Another side is the recurring exhibition of the fact that these witnesses were persecuted only by those whose action should create no bias against the persecuted.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The cause of medical materialism is the natural bias of physicians towards explaining the health and disease of mind by the health and disease of body.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But the Christian bias is sure to make theologians, who borrow a doctrine of the Absolute, interpret it in a Christian sense; hence we may consider it something of an accident that even an Augustine fails exactly to put the argument in form.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			All that Hauch wrote is marked by great qualities, and by distinction; he had a native bias towards the mystical, which, however, he learned to keep in abeyance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bias of modern practice, in short, is towards milder methods, not only in treatment, but in those anticipatory processes which may render imprisonment unnecessary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Despite the almost inevitable US bias, it is still worth a visit.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			One of them seeing Bias without anything, advised him to follow the example of the rest.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>codon bias.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>prejudice</definition>
		<definition>slant</definition>
		<definition>influence</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>leaning</syn>
			<syn>bent</syn>
			<syn>tendency</syn>
			<syn>inclination</syn>
			<syn>penchant</syn>
			<syn>intolerance</syn>
			<syn>bigotry</syn>
			<syn>propensity</syn>
			<syn>favouritism</syn>
			<syn>predisposition</syn>
			<syn>nepotism</syn>
			<syn>unfairness</syn>
			<syn>predilection</syn>
			<syn>proclivity</syn>
			<syn>partiality</syn>
			<syn>narrow-mindedness</syn>
			<syn>proneness</syn>
			<syn>one-sidedness</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>cross</syn>
			<syn>angle</syn>
			<syn>diagonal line</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>influence</syn>
			<syn>colour</syn>
			<syn>weight</syn>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>distort</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>warp</syn>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>predispose</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>equity</ant>
			<ant>equality</ant>
			<ant>fairness</ant>
			<ant>neutrality</ant>
			<ant>objectivity</ant>
			<ant>impartiality</ant>
			<ant>open-mindedness</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>crack</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>
			to break something so that it does not separate, but very thin lines appear on its surface, or to become broken in this way
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>çatla(t)mak, yar(ýl)mak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Linda cracked her tooth when she fell.</ex>
			<ex>The concrete had started to crack.</ex>
			<ex>cracked dishes</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>to open an egg or nut by breaking its shell</eng-def>
		<tr-def>kabuðunu kýrmak</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>to hit a part of your body against something hard, by accident</eng-def>
		<tr-def>kazara vurmak, çarpmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He cracked his head on the shelf.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>to solve a difficult problem</eng-def>
		<tr-def>zor bir problemi çözmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>It took three months to crack the enemy's code.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>get cracking</title>
		<eng-def>to start doing something quickly</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir þeyi yapmaya süratle baþlamak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Let's get cracking! We've only got two days to finish.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>
			to lose control of your emotions and be unable to deal with a situation
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>sinir krizi geçirmek, kendinden geçmek, kontrolü kaybetmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He finally cracked after years of stress.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack</title>
		<eng-def>
			to make a sudden, short noise, or to make something make this noise
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>þýrak' diye ses çýkar(t)mak, þaklamak, þaklatmak</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>crack a joke</title>
		<eng-def>to tell a joke</eng-def>
		<tr-def>fýkra anlatmak/patlatmak/söylemek</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>He paused near the crack in the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence>He'd felt the earth crack open once before.</sentence>
		<sentence>He too is helping to crack it.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She could wear men's clothes and crack that whip all she wanted, but she was still a woman at heart - and he knew it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There was a small scream, then the crack of bone and ripping of flesh.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Katie jerked on the dairy door and the crack of frozen boards echoed in the pregnant silence.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>A small crack traveled about half way down the piece of wood.</sentence>
		<sentence>Connor wants to leave at the crack of dawn.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She peered through the crack in the door until certain they both entered the bedroom, then opened the closet door and slid out the opened front door.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The crack of the wooden door registered a short second before his hand gripped her throat.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"Just colder," she added with a shiver, as if to apology for the crack in her voice.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>I caught the crack about 'that side of the court room.'</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The servers come and join you at your table and crack smart jokes about your order, but it's all in good fun and part of its charm.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>crack is allowed in the first instance with no harmful effects.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"If—" She snapped her head back and felt it crack him in the nose.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The presence of a small quantity of the hard cementite ought naturally to strengthen the mass, by opposing the tendency of the soft ferrite to flow under any stress applied to it; but more cementite by its brittleness naturally weakens the mass, causing it to crack open under the distortion which stress inevitably causes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The wire gives the glass great advantages in the event of fracture from a blow or from fire, but owing to the difference in thermal expansion between wire and glass, there is a strong tendency for such " wired glass " to crack spontaneously.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			My 'lights out' crack was uncalled for, but so was what you said.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Natasha glanced at her and at the crack in the pantry door, and it seemed to her that she remembered the light falling through that crack once before and Sonya passing with a glass in her hand.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She inserted the blade in a crack along the edge of the brush and it separated into two pieces.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>break</definition>
		<definition>snap</definition>
		<definition>hit</definition>
		<definition>cleave</definition>
		<definition>solve</definition>
		<definition>break down</definition>
		<definition>break</definition>
		<definition>split</definition>
		<definition>snap</definition>
		<definition>blow</definition>
		<definition>attempt</definition>
		<definition>joke</definition>
		<definition>first-class</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>break</syn>
			<syn>split</syn>
			<syn>burst</syn>
			<syn>snap</syn>
			<syn>fracture</syn>
			<syn>splinter</syn>
			<syn>craze</syn>
			<syn>rive</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>snap</syn>
			<syn>ring</syn>
			<syn>crash</syn>
			<syn>burst</syn>
			<syn>explode</syn>
			<syn>crackle</syn>
			<syn>pop</syn>
			<syn>detonate</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>hit</syn>
			<syn>clip</syn>
			<syn>slap</syn>
			<syn>smack</syn>
			<syn>thump</syn>
			<syn>buffet</syn>
			<syn>clout</syn>
			<syn>cuff</syn>
			<syn>whack</syn>
			<syn>wallop</syn>
			<syn>chop</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>cleave</syn>
			<syn>break</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>solve</syn>
			<syn>work out</syn>
			<syn>resolve</syn>
			<syn>interpret</syn>
			<syn>clarify</syn>
			<syn>clear up</syn>
			<syn>fathom</syn>
			<syn>decipher</syn>
			<syn>suss (out)</syn>
			<syn>disentangle</syn>
			<syn>elucidate</syn>
			<syn>get to the bottom of</syn>
			<syn>get the answer to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>break down</syn>
			<syn>collapse</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>give in</syn>
			<syn>give way</syn>
			<syn>succumb</syn>
			<syn>lose control</syn>
			<syn>be overcome</syn>
			<syn>go to pieces</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>break</syn>
			<syn>chink</syn>
			<syn>gap</syn>
			<syn>breach</syn>
			<syn>fracture</syn>
			<syn>rift</syn>
			<syn>cleft</syn>
			<syn>crevice</syn>
			<syn>fissure</syn>
			<syn>cranny</syn>
			<syn>interstice</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>split</syn>
			<syn>break</syn>
			<syn>chip</syn>
			<syn>breach</syn>
			<syn>fracture</syn>
			<syn>rupture</syn>
			<syn>cleft</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>snap</syn>
			<syn>pop</syn>
			<syn>crash</syn>
			<syn>burst</syn>
			<syn>explosion</syn>
			<syn>clap</syn>
			<syn>report</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>blow</syn>
			<syn>slap</syn>
			<syn>smack</syn>
			<syn>thump</syn>
			<syn>clout</syn>
			<syn>cuff</syn>
			<syn>whack</syn>
			<syn>wallop</syn>
			<syn>clip</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>attempt</syn>
			<syn>go</syn>
			<syn>try</syn>
			<syn>shot</syn>
			<syn>opportunity</syn>
			<syn>stab</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>joke</syn>
			<syn>dig</syn>
			<syn>gag</syn>
			<syn>quip</syn>
			<syn>jibe</syn>
			<syn>wisecrack</syn>
			<syn>witticism</syn>
			<syn>funny remark</syn>
			<syn>smart-alecky remark</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>first-class</syn>
			<syn>choice</syn>
			<syn>excellent</syn>
			<syn>ace</syn>
			<syn>elite</syn>
			<syn>superior</syn>
			<syn>world-class</syn>
			<syn>first-rate</syn>
			<syn>hand-picked</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>campaign</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>campaign</title>
		<eng-def>
			a series of organized activities or events intended to achieve a result
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>kampanya, düzenlenen bir dizi faaliyetler bütünü</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an advertising/election campaign</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>campaign</title>
		<eng-def>a series of military attacks</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir dizi askeri saldýrý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bombing campaign</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			If I'm going to be your campaign manager, leave the business to me.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>I'd better get my campaign manager cracking.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			By the end of the four-month campaign, the White House would receive two million dimes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Did you take part in the campaign? he asked.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Six ladies, all carrying campaign signs, formed an honor guard around the vehicle.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			During his campaign and his time in office, the extent of the effect of his polio was kept from the public, but the fact he had the disease was commonly known.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The old prince and his son seemed to have changed roles since the campaign of 1805.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He accomplished a successful campaign in 1868 against Bokhara, capturing Samarkand and gradually subjugating the whole country.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			During the campaign he met his wife, Anita, who became his inseparable companion and mother of three children, Anita, Ricciotti and Menotti.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Then followed in 1875 the campaign against Khokand, in which Kaufmann defeated the khan, Nasr-ed-din.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Dean had blanked his campaign for sheriff from his mind, but now it returned with a headache fury.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Martha bounced around, thrilled to be back in the routine, and joined Fred in passing out more campaign literature.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			1g the German King Lothair, whom he induced to undertake a campaign against Anacletus.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The actions of Napoleon and Alexander, on whose words the event seemed to hang, were as little voluntary as the actions of any soldier who was drawn into the campaign by lot or by conscription.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He then makes his Persian expedition; the Indian campaign gives occasion for descriptions of all kinds of wonders.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There followed a campaign against the idols whose temples and books were destroyed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The campaign of Mons.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"But still this does not mean that the campaign is over," said Prince Andrew.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			had succeeded in forming a new union of royalists and presbyterians, and another campaign became inevitable.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Louis took an active part in the campaign and fought heroically at Jarnac and Moncontour.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>drive</definition>
		<definition>operation</definition>
		<definition>crusade</definition>
		<definition>canvass</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>drive</syn>
			<syn>appeal</syn>
			<syn>movement</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>offensive</syn>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>operation</syn>
			<syn>drive</syn>
			<syn>attack</syn>
			<syn>movement</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>offensive</syn>
			<syn>expedition</syn>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
			<syn>jihad</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
			<syn>press</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>encourage</syn>
			<syn>urge</syn>
			<syn>boost</syn>
			<syn>petition</syn>
			<syn>back</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>canvass</syn>
			<syn>electioneer</syn>
			<syn>solicit votes</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bias</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>bias</title>
		<eng-def>
			a situation in which you support or oppose someone or something in an unfair way because you are influenced by your personal opinions
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>önyargý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bias towards/against private education</ex>
			<ex>
				The news channel has been accused of bias in favour of the government.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>His natural bias was to respect things as they were.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This document provides guidance on the stages in scheme development at which optimism bias can be reduced.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The townspeople show a bias in favour of French habits and fashions.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To illustrate the self-serving bias with regard to success, I will draw on my own experiences.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His natural parts were excellent; and a strong bias in the direction of abstract thought, and mathematics in particular, was noticeable at an early date.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This bias is reflected in the maxim that "correction should precede interpretation," which is no more than a half-truth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It gives copious details, and, as he had access to the correspondence and official documents of the Spanish leaders, it is, although necessarily possessing bias, the fullest and most authentic record existing of the events it relates.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sovereign as compared with her ministers has, because she is the sovereign, the advantage of long experience, wide survey, elevated position and entire disconnexion from the bias of party.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its author, with a considerable mathematical and mechanical bias, reckoned entirely with the quantity, not with the quality of his units, and relied almost implicitly upon his formulae.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			That phrase accurately describes the prevalent bias of its author's mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Lotze was a man of considerable attainments in special science; perhaps he reveals here the bias of the scientific mind, and possibly even its limitations.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He adhered henceforth to the army party, but with a constant bias in favour of the king.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Another side is the recurring exhibition of the fact that these witnesses were persecuted only by those whose action should create no bias against the persecuted.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The cause of medical materialism is the natural bias of physicians towards explaining the health and disease of mind by the health and disease of body.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But the Christian bias is sure to make theologians, who borrow a doctrine of the Absolute, interpret it in a Christian sense; hence we may consider it something of an accident that even an Augustine fails exactly to put the argument in form.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			All that Hauch wrote is marked by great qualities, and by distinction; he had a native bias towards the mystical, which, however, he learned to keep in abeyance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bias of modern practice, in short, is towards milder methods, not only in treatment, but in those anticipatory processes which may render imprisonment unnecessary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Despite the almost inevitable US bias, it is still worth a visit.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			One of them seeing Bias without anything, advised him to follow the example of the rest.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>codon bias.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>prejudice</definition>
		<definition>slant</definition>
		<definition>influence</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>leaning</syn>
			<syn>bent</syn>
			<syn>tendency</syn>
			<syn>inclination</syn>
			<syn>penchant</syn>
			<syn>intolerance</syn>
			<syn>bigotry</syn>
			<syn>propensity</syn>
			<syn>favouritism</syn>
			<syn>predisposition</syn>
			<syn>nepotism</syn>
			<syn>unfairness</syn>
			<syn>predilection</syn>
			<syn>proclivity</syn>
			<syn>partiality</syn>
			<syn>narrow-mindedness</syn>
			<syn>proneness</syn>
			<syn>one-sidedness</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>cross</syn>
			<syn>angle</syn>
			<syn>diagonal line</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>influence</syn>
			<syn>colour</syn>
			<syn>weight</syn>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>distort</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>warp</syn>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>predispose</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>equity</ant>
			<ant>equality</ant>
			<ant>fairness</ant>
			<ant>neutrality</ant>
			<ant>objectivity</ant>
			<ant>impartiality</ant>
			<ant>open-mindedness</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>almighty</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>almighty</title>
		<eng-def>very strong or forceful</eng-def>
		<tr-def>gï¿½ï¿½lï¿½, ilahi, ï¿½ok kudretli, kudretli</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>All of a sudden I heard an almighty bang in the kitchen.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>almighty</title>
		<eng-def>having the power to do everything, like a god</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ilahi, kudretli, Tanrï¿½ gibi gï¿½ï¿½lï¿½</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Almighty God</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>I believe in God (the) Father almighty; II.</sentence>
		<sentence>The vision of the Almighty is full of majesty and peace.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I raise fervent prayers to Heaven that the Almighty may exalt the race of the just, and mercifully fulfill the desires of Your Majesty.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Then he beholds the Almighty on His throne surrounded by the four and twenty elders and the four living creatures.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Forbid it, Almighty God !</sentence>
		<sentence>
			We find " suffered " in the creed of Milan, " descended into hell " in the creed of Aquileia, the Danubian lands and Syria; the words " God " and " almighty " were shortly added to clause 7 in the Spanish creed; " life everlasting " had stood from an early date in the African creed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It would be so unfair to so many people if we quit, but God almighty, it's difficult and scary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In 1793 he declared himself the apostle of a new religion, "the nephew of the Almighty, and prince of the Hebrews, appointed to lead them to the land of Canaan."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Scotus extends the number of theological doctrines which are not, according to him, susceptible of philosophical proof, including in this class the creation of the world out of nothing, the immortality of the human soul, and even the existence of an almighty divine cause of the universe (though he admits the possibility of proving an ultimate cause superior to all else).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Bless his counsels, his undertakings, and his work; strengthen his kingdom by Thine almighty hand, and give him victory over his enemy, even as Thou gavest Moses the victory over Amalek, Gideon over Midian, and David over Goliath.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His father keeps a cookshop here by the Stone Bridge, and you know there was a large icon of God Almighty painted with a scepter in one hand and an orb in the other.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			the religious temper: " Most glorious of immortals, 0 Zeus of many names, almighty and everlasting, sovereign of nature, directing all in accordance with law, thee it is fitting that all mortals should address....
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Only let everyone keep the thought that Satan also stands under the commission of the Almighty God, and that no one must suppose that by leading back his sins to a Satanic temptation he can get rid of his own guilt.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The chief points were (I) the lawfulness and expediency of certain terms employed by the Jesuits in naming God Almighty, such as Tien, " Heaven," and Shang-ti, " Supreme Ruler" or "Emperor," instead of Tien-Chu, " Lord of Heaven," and in particular the erection of inscribed tablets in the churches, on which these terms were made use of; 2 (2) in respect to the ceremonial offerings made in honour of Confucius, and of personal ancestors, which Ricci had recognized as merely "civil" observances; (3) the erection of tablets in honour of ancestors in private houses; and (4), more generally,- sanction and favour accorded to ancient Chinese sacred books and philosophical doctrine, as not really trespassing;on Christian faith.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But there was no getting over the fact that his father had sworn "before the Almighty and His judgment seat" to pardon him and let him live in peace if he returned to Russia.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The truth of this will be apparent if it is considered that the Moral and Political Philosophy admittedly embodies two presuppositions: (I) that "God Almighty wills and wishes the happiness of His creatures," and (2) that adequate motives must be supplied to virtue by a system of future rewards and punishments.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The following may be instanced: " Lord of mercy and of might "; " Brightest and best of the sons of the morning "; " By cool Siloam's shady rill "; " God, that madest earth and heaven "; " The Lord of might from Sinai's brow "; " Holy, holy, holy, Lord God Almighty "; " From Greenland's icy mountains "; " The Lord will come, the earth shall quake "; The Son of God goes forth to war."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"I will never," he declared, "allow to come between Almighty God and this country a blotted parchment, to rule us with paragraphs, and to replace the ancient, sacred bond of loyalty."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I believe in one Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of God, born of God, God of God, Light of Light, almighty of almighty, true God of true God, born before the ages, not made, by whom all things were made in heaven and in earth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The old familiar name Yahweh became a secret; its place was taken by such general expressions as the Holy, the Almighty, the Majesty on High, the King of Kings, and also by the simple word "Heaven."
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>all-powerful</definition>
		<definition>great</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>all-powerful</syn>
			<syn>supreme</syn>
			<syn>absolute</syn>
			<syn>unlimited</syn>
			<syn>invincible</syn>
			<syn>omnipotent</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>great</syn>
			<syn>terrible</syn>
			<syn>enormous</syn>
			<syn>desperate</syn>
			<syn>severe</syn>
			<syn>intense</syn>
			<syn>awful</syn>
			<syn>loud</syn>
			<syn>excessive</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>weak</ant>
			<ant>helpless</ant>
			<ant>powerless</ant>
			<ant>impotent</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>poor</ant>
			<ant>slight</ant>
			<ant>tame</ant>
			<ant>feeble</ant>
			<ant>insignificant</ant>
			<ant>paltry</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>cultivate</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>cultivate</title>
		<eng-def>to prepare land and grow crops on it</eng-def>
		<tr-def>topraðý iþlemek, ekip biçmek, sürüp ekmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>This shrub is cultivated in Europe as a herb used in cooking.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>cultivate</title>
		<eng-def>to try to develop or improve something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir þeyi geliþtirmek, ilerletmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She has cultivated an image as a tough negotiator.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Why anyone would cultivate that nasty habit is a mystery to me.</sentence>
		<sentence>Some live in settled communities and roughly cultivate the soil.</sentence>
		<sentence>They are very easy to cultivate and do not require lifting.</sentence>
		<sentence>The insects cultivate their fungus, weeding out.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Crispi was prepared to cultivate good relations with France, but refused to yield to pressure or to submit to dicta - tion; and in this attitude he was firmly supported by the bulk of his fellow-countrymen.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Nearly all the land is in the hands of peasant proprietors, who cultivate sweet potatoes, peas, beans, corn, &c., and rear sheep and goats.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The Piojes live in permanent communities and cultivate the soil.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is not desirable to cultivate a respect for the law, so much as for the right.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Cultivate poverty like a garden herb, like sage.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The mountaineers breed some cattle and sheep, and cultivate small fields on the mountain-sides.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He must be in touch with the actual life of the community he is studying, and cultivate " that openness and alertness of the mind, that sensitiveness of the judgment, which can rapidly grasp the significance of at first sight unrelated discoveries or events."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Great part is mountainous, but some very fertile valleys exist, to cultivate which 2000 yoke of oxen are employed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			ager, field, and colere, to cultivate), the science, art and industry of utilizing the soil so as to produce the means of human subsistence, embracing in its widest sense the rearing of live-stock as well as the raising of crops.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He took a foremost part in almost every good work in his diocese, social or educational, political or religious; while he found time also to cultivate friendly relations with thinking men and women of all schools, and to help all and sundry who came to him for advice and assistance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Not till the 13th of February were the miserable remnants of the population permitted to rebuild their houses and cultivate their fields once more.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			If the debtor did not cultivate the field himself he had to pay for the cultivation, but if the cultivation was already finished he must harvest it himself and pay his debt from the crop. If the cultivator did not get a crop this would not cancel his contract.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			These cultivate gambier and pepper successfully in Bintang, and there is a considerable trade in wood.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the moist bottom-lands along the rivers it is the custom to throw the soil up in high beds with the plough, and then to cultivate them deep. This is the more common method of drainage, but it is expensive, as it has to be renewed every few years.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			While their neighbours, the Malays, Papuans and Polynesians, all cultivate the soil, and build substantial huts and houses, the Australian natives do neither.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Hansen set himself the task of studying the properties of the varieties of yeast, and to do this he had to cultivate each variety in a pure state.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>farm</definition>
		<definition>develop</definition>
		<definition>court</definition>
		<definition>foster</definition>
		<definition>improve</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>farm</syn>
			<syn>work</syn>
			<syn>plant</syn>
			<syn>tend</syn>
			<syn>till</syn>
			<syn>harvest</syn>
			<syn>plough</syn>
			<syn>bring under cultivation</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>develop</syn>
			<syn>establish</syn>
			<syn>acquire</syn>
			<syn>foster</syn>
			<syn>pursue</syn>
			<syn>devote yourself to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>court</syn>
			<syn>seek out</syn>
			<syn>run after</syn>
			<syn>butter up</syn>
			<syn>associate with</syn>
			<syn>consort with</syn>
			<syn>dance attendance upon</syn>
			<syn>seek someone's company or friendship</syn>
			<syn>take trouble or pains with</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>foster</syn>
			<syn>further</syn>
			<syn>forward</syn>
			<syn>encourage</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>improve</syn>
			<syn>better</syn>
			<syn>train</syn>
			<syn>discipline</syn>
			<syn>polish</syn>
			<syn>refine</syn>
			<syn>elevate</syn>
			<syn>enrich</syn>
			<syn>civilize</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>basis</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>on a daily/monthly/regular, etc basis</title>
		<eng-def>how often something happens or is done</eng-def>
		<tr-def>günlük/aylýk/düzenli olarak, aralýklarla</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Meetings are held on a weekly basis.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>on a commercial/full-time/percentage, etc basis</title>
		<eng-def>the way something happens or is organized</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			ticari/tam zamanlý/yüzde vs. esasýna dayalý olarak, þeklinde, biçiminde
		</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>We will consider claims for asylum on a case by case basis.</ex>
			<ex>We deal with each case on an individual basis.</ex>
			<ex>She's having private lessons on a one-to-one basis.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>basis</title>
		<eng-def>the reason for something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>dayanak, bir þeyin dayandýðý nokta</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Marks are awarded on the basis of progress and performance.</ex>
			<ex>There is no legal basis for his claim.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>basis</title>
		<eng-def>a situation, fact, or idea from which something can develop</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir gerçek veya fikrin çýkýþ noktasý, durumu</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Dani's essay can serve as a basis for our discussion.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>So you're on a first name basis with him, huh?</sentence>
		<sentence>It wasn't as if there was any basis for the feeling.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I remembered a judge had tossed out a search warrant obtained only on the basis of our tip.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>In 1840 we have the first safe basis for comparison of strength.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The French census uses the commune as the basis of its returns, and employs the following classifications in respect to communal population: (I) Total communal population.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			No doubt because she didn't have to do it on a regular basis as Alex did.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Was that Shipton's basis for everything?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			in his Encyclical of August 4, 1879, which directed the clergy to take the teachings of Aquinas as the basis of their theological position.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>This is the basis of real intercourse.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Now, on a regular basis, videos appear which bring to life something that would otherwise be merely an ill-formed image in our minds.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Department personnel operated on the basis of out-of-sight, out-of-mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even the Chinese philosopher was wise enough to regard the individual as the basis of the empire.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What if you could do agriculture perfectly on a per-grape basis, each grape getting individual attention?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The following tables, showing the growth of the largest towns in France, are drawn up on the basis of the fourth classification, which is used throughout this work in the articles on French towns, except where otherwise stated.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			trans., from 2nd German ed., The Philosophy of Religion on the Basis of its History, 4 vols., 1886-1888).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			With calm courage he returned to his poverty and his favourite studies, and in 1725 published the first edition of the work that forms the basis of his renown, Principii d'una scienza nuova.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In July 1865, when politics had shifted from the basis of the 1861 Constitution, he laid down office, and retired from public affairs.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			- Although the legal basis for the final stage is found in the legislation of the time of Moses (latter part of the second millennium B.C.), it is in reality scarcely earlier than the 5th century B.C., and the Jewish theory finds analogies when developments of the Levitical service are referred to David (I Chron.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Still, a case that spawned a novel basis for argument was always a welcomed diversion from their increasing caseload.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It couldn't have been better, but entertaining three men on a daily basis was a mental workout.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>arrangement</definition>
		<definition>foundation</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>arrangement</syn>
			<syn>way</syn>
			<syn>system</syn>
			<syn>footing</syn>
			<syn>agreement</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>foundation</syn>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>base</syn>
			<syn>ground</syn>
			<syn>footing</syn>
			<syn>theory</syn>
			<syn>bottom</syn>
			<syn>principle</syn>
			<syn>premise</syn>
			<syn>starting point</syn>
			<syn>groundwork</syn>
			<syn>point of departure</syn>
			<syn>principal element</syn>
			<syn>chief ingredient</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bother</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>bother</title>
		<eng-def>
			to annoy someone by trying to get their attention when they do not want to see you or talk to you
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>taciz etmek, canýný sýkmak, uðraþmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Don't bother your father when he's working.</ex>
			<ex>Sorry to bother you, but could you spare any change?</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bother</title>
		<eng-def>to make someone feel worried or upset</eng-def>
		<tr-def>birini üzmek, endiþeye sevketmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Living on my own doesn't bother me at all.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bother</title>
		<eng-def>to make the effort to do something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>uðraþmak, didinmek, çaba sarfetmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Don't bother making the bed - I'll do it later.</ex>
			<ex>He didn't even bother to call.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>can't be bothered</title>
		<eng-def>
			If you can't be bothered to do something, you are too lazy or tired to do it.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>hiç iþim yoktu sanki, bana ne</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>I can't be bothered to iron my clothes.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>not bothered</title>
		<eng-def>
			If you are not bothered about something, it is not important to you and does not worry you.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>zahmet etme, kendini yorma, boþver, aldýrma, tasalanma</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>"Do you want tea or coffee?" "Either, I'm not bothered."</ex>
			<ex>I'm not bothered whether I win or lose.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>I didn't even bother to ask.</sentence>
		<sentence>Look, I'm sorry to bother you with my troubles.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"I'm sorry to bother you," she said again, unable to see his face in the shadows of the dimly lit room.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>And that doesn't bother you?</sentence>
		<sentence>This does not bother you?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"Sorry to bother you, but I have a message for Howard," she said.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was as if he said to them: I know you, I know you, but why should I bother about you?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>We didn't bother to argue with Quinn.</sentence>
		<sentence>That man will never bother you again, he said.</sentence>
		<sentence>. .but all these facts bother me.</sentence>
		<sentence>Doesn't it bother you?</sentence>
		<sentence>Cold doesn't bother me any more than it does you.</sentence>
		<sentence>Why was she letting it bother her anyway?</sentence>
		<sentence>It doesn't bother me at all.</sentence>
		<sentence>I think I'll sleep in tomorrow, so don't bother to get up early.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Do you ever bother to see if the moms want to have a baby angel in their lives?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"Does nothing bother you?" he asked without heat, knowing the answer.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Don't bother to ask questions because you won't get many answers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			If you tell me to leave at the end of it, I'll never bother you again.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Nice cars, nice enough house, but the tour bus doesn't bother to point out their digs.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>concern yourself</definition>
		<definition>trouble</definition>
		<definition>pester</definition>
		<definition>trouble</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>concern yourself</syn>
			<syn>take the time</syn>
			<syn>make the effort</syn>
			<syn>go to the trouble</syn>
			<syn>trouble yourself</syn>
			<syn>burden yourself</syn>
			<syn>inconvenience yourself</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>trouble</syn>
			<syn>concern</syn>
			<syn>worry</syn>
			<syn>upset</syn>
			<syn>alarm</syn>
			<syn>disturb</syn>
			<syn>distress</syn>
			<syn>annoy</syn>
			<syn>dismay</syn>
			<syn>gall</syn>
			<syn>disconcert</syn>
			<syn>vex</syn>
			<syn>perturb</syn>
			<syn>faze</syn>
			<syn>put or get someone's back up</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>pester</syn>
			<syn>plague</syn>
			<syn>irritate</syn>
			<syn>put out</syn>
			<syn>harass</syn>
			<syn>nag</syn>
			<syn>hassle</syn>
			<syn>inconvenience</syn>
			<syn>molest</syn>
			<syn>get on your nerves</syn>
			<syn>nark</syn>
			<syn>bend someone's ear</syn>
			<syn>give someone grief</syn>
			<syn>get on your wick</syn>
			<syn>breathe down someone's neck</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>trouble</syn>
			<syn>problem</syn>
			<syn>worry</syn>
			<syn>difficulty</syn>
			<syn>strain</syn>
			<syn>grief</syn>
			<syn>fuss</syn>
			<syn>pest</syn>
			<syn>irritation</syn>
			<syn>hassle</syn>
			<syn>nuisance</syn>
			<syn>flurry</syn>
			<syn>uphill</syn>
			<syn>inconvenience</syn>
			<syn>annoyance</syn>
			<syn>aggravation</syn>
			<syn>vexation</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>help</ant>
			<ant>support</ant>
			<ant>further</ant>
			<ant>aid</ant>
			<ant>assist</ant>
			<ant>relieve</ant>
			<ant>facilitate</ant>
			<ant>succour</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>help</ant>
			<ant>service</ant>
			<ant>benefit</ant>
			<ant>aid</ant>
			<ant>advantage</ant>
			<ant>comfort</ant>
			<ant>convenience</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bear</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to accept someone or something unpleasant</eng-def>
		<tr-def>tahammül etmek, kaldýrmak, dayanmak, katlanmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She couldn't bear the thought of him suffering.</ex>
			<ex>I like her, but I can't bear her friends.</ex>
			<ex>How can you bear to watch?</ex>
			<ex>The pain was too much to bear.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear a resemblance/relation, etc to sb/sth</title>
		<eng-def>to be similar to someone or something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>benzemek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He bears a striking resemblance to his father.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to carry something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>taþýmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He came in, bearing a tray of drinks.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to support the weight of something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>çekmek, götürmek, kaldýrmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>I don't think that chair will bear his weight.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear the responsibility/cost, etc</title>
		<eng-def>
			to accept that you are responsible for something, you should pay for something, etc
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>sorumluluðu üstlenmek, maliyetine katlanmak, sonucuna razý olmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				He must bear some responsibility for the appalling conditions in the prison.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to continue to have a bad feeling towards someone</eng-def>
		<tr-def>çekmek, katlanmak, tahammül etmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				They were rude to her in the past, but she's not the kind of woman who bears grudges (= continues to be angry).
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to give birth to a child</eng-def>
		<tr-def>doðurmak, dünyaya getirmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She has been told that she will never bear children.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to have or show a particular name, picture, or symbol</eng-def>
		<tr-def>hususi bir isim, resim veya sembolü olmak, göstermek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>The shop bore his family name.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear left/right</title>
		<eng-def>to turn left or right</eng-def>
		<tr-def>sola/saða dönmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Bear right at the next set of traffic lights.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>I could not bear to see her punished.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It wasn't the first time she had seen a bear track, but it was the first time she had seen one that fresh.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Finally Katie could bear the silence no longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>Bear with me a little longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>Finally she could bear the suspense no longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>I can't bear it!</sentence>
		<sentence>I can't bear those old men!</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bear stopped and stared at him, but made no move to run away.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			If the company pollutes, it should bear the cost of that pollution.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			When she heard this Sonya blushed so that tears came into her eyes and, unable to bear the looks turned upon her, ran away into the dancing hall, whirled round it at full speed with her dress puffed out like a balloon, and, flushed and smiling, plumped down on the floor.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The bear lifted her nose, testing the breeze.</sentence>
		<sentence>Alex fired twice more and the bear dropped to the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He seemed unable to bear the sight of tears and was ready to cry himself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>What was it she had heard about bear attacks?</sentence>
		<sentence>He could not bear to see her grief.</sentence>
		<sentence>When the bear continued toward him, he fired.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But go with the firm intention of killing your man as quickly and surely as possible, and then all will be right, as our bear huntsman at Kostroma used to tell me.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The third time that he thrust out the weapon there was a loud roar and a fall, and suddenly at his feet appeared the form of a great red bear, which was nearly as big as the horse and much stronger and fiercer.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			And there was the bear swimming about with the policeman on his back!
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She was sure he would speak soft, tender words to her such as her father had uttered before his death, and that she would not be able to bear it and would burst into sobs in his presence.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>carry</definition>
		<definition>hold</definition>
		<definition>support</definition>
		<definition>display</definition>
		<definition>suffer</definition>
		<definition>bring yourself to</definition>
		<definition>take on</definition>
		<definition>produce</definition>
		<definition>earn</definition>
		<definition>give birth to</definition>
		<definition>exhibit</definition>
		<definition>conduct</definition>
		<definition>turn</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>take</syn>
			<syn>move</syn>
			<syn>bring</syn>
			<syn>lift</syn>
			<syn>transfer</syn>
			<syn>transport</syn>
			<syn>haul</syn>
			<syn>transmit</syn>
			<syn>convey</syn>
			<syn>relay</syn>
			<syn>tote</syn>
			<syn>hump</syn>
			<syn>lug</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>pack</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>shoulder</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>hold up</syn>
			<syn>keep up</syn>
			<syn>uphold</syn>
			<syn>withstand</syn>
			<syn>bear up under</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>display</syn>
			<syn>have</syn>
			<syn>show</syn>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>possess</syn>
			<syn>exhibit</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>suffer</syn>
			<syn>feel</syn>
			<syn>experience</syn>
			<syn>go through</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>stomach</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>undergo</syn>
			<syn>admit</syn>
			<syn>brook</syn>
			<syn>hack</syn>
			<syn>abide</syn>
			<syn>put up with</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>allow</syn>
			<syn>accept</syn>
			<syn>permit</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>tolerate</syn>
			<syn>hack</syn>
			<syn>abide</syn>
			<syn>be doing with</syn>
			<syn>countenance</syn>
			<syn>bring yourself to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>take on</syn>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>accept</syn>
			<syn>shoulder</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>absorb</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>produce</syn>
			<syn>give</syn>
			<syn>provide</syn>
			<syn>develop</syn>
			<syn>generate</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>bring forth</syn>
			<syn>give forth</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>earn</syn>
			<syn>make</syn>
			<syn>get</syn>
			<syn>receive</syn>
			<syn>gain</syn>
			<syn>net</syn>
			<syn>collect</syn>
			<syn>realize</syn>
			<syn>obtain</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>bring in</syn>
			<syn>gross</syn>
			<syn>reap</syn>
			<syn>procure</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>produce</syn>
			<syn>deliver</syn>
			<syn>breed</syn>
			<syn>beget</syn>
			<syn>give birth to</syn>
			<syn>bring forth</syn>
			<syn>be delivered of</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>exhibit</syn>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>maintain</syn>
			<syn>entertain</syn>
			<syn>harbour</syn>
			<syn>cherish</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>conduct</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>move</syn>
			<syn>deport</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>turn</syn>
			<syn>tack</syn>
			<syn>veer</syn>
			<syn>swerve</syn>
			<syn>shift</syn>
			<syn>sheer</syn>
			<syn>change direction</syn>
			<syn>change course</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>drop</ant>
			<ant>shed</ant>
			<ant>put down</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>drop</ant>
			<ant>give up</ant>
			<ant>abandon</ant>
			<ant>relinquish</ant>
			<ant>discontinue</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>abstract</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>relating to ideas and not real things</eng-def>
		<tr-def>soyut</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an abstract concept</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>
			Abstract art involves shapes and colours and not images of real things or people.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			gerçek nesne ve kiþilerin imgelerinden çok renk ve þekilleri içeren soyut sanat
		</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			They had no abstract ideas; in their minds all was concrete, visible and tangible.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>His abstract submission met the deadline.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Choose five abstract nouns relating to recent conversational themes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Do you have an abstract of a paper or presentation you would like to give?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He presented abstract concepts with empirical data.</sentence>
		<sentence>Can I have an abstract of the article?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Thus Descartes gave to modern geometry that abstract and general character in which consists its superiority to the geometry of the ancients.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He was searching for an abstract expressionist painting by de Kooning.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Congress (London, 18 95), p. 735 (English Abstract, p. 748).</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It does not appear, however, that a regularly organized or numerous Orphic sect ever existed, nor that Orphism ever became popular; it was too abstract, too full of symbolism.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He asked me how I had taught Helen adjectives and the names of abstract ideas like goodness and happiness.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What remains to be done is, not to explain how such a world manages to be what it is, nor how we came to form these notions, but merely this - to expel from the circle and totality of our conceptions those abstract notions which are inconsistent and jarring, or to remodel and define them so that they may constitute a consistent and harmonious view.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Moreover, the abstract terms stem, leaf, root, &c., are absolutely indispensable; and are continually used in this sense by the most ardent organographers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Abstract expressionism was a New York painting movement of the 1940's with its artistic roots based upon abstract art.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Secondly: from the discrepancy between the pure abstract law of self-consistent reason and the pleasuretinged nature of man, we infer or postulate Immortality.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was evident that Prince Andrew was not interested in such abstract conversation.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the very nature of things, articulation is an unsatisfactory means of education; while the use of the manual alphabet quickens and invigorates mental activity, since through it the deaf child is brought into close contact with the English language, and the highest and most abstract ideas may be conveyed to the mind readily and accurately.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The neuter term brahma is used in the Rigveda both in the abstract sense of "devotion, worship," and in the concrete sense of "devotional rite, prayer, hymn."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The first, De Sancta Trinitate, is addressed to Symmachus (Domino Patri Symmacho), and the result of the short discussion, which is of an abstract nature, and deals partly with the ten categories, is that unity is predicated absolutely, or, in regard to the substance of the Deity, trinity is predicated relatively.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Klebs, Guide to Exhibit of the German Amber Industry at World's Fair (St Louis, 1904); and abstract by G.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>theoretical</definition>
		<definition>symbolic</definition>
		<definition>summary</definition>
		<definition>extract</definition>
		<definition>summarize</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>theoretical</syn>
			<syn>general</syn>
			<syn>academic</syn>
			<syn>intellectual</syn>
			<syn>subtle</syn>
			<syn>profound</syn>
			<syn>philosophical</syn>
			<syn>speculative</syn>
			<syn>unrealistic</syn>
			<syn>conceptual</syn>
			<syn>indefinite</syn>
			<syn>deep</syn>
			<syn>occult</syn>
			<syn>hypothetical</syn>
			<syn>generalized</syn>
			<syn>impractical</syn>
			<syn>arcane</syn>
			<syn>notional</syn>
			<syn>abstruse</syn>
			<syn>recondite</syn>
			<syn>theoretic</syn>
			<syn>conjectural</syn>
			<syn>unpractical</syn>
			<syn>nonconcrete</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>symbolic</syn>
			<syn>figurative</syn>
			<syn>emblematic</syn>
			<syn>impressionistic</syn>
			<syn>non-representational</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summary</syn>
			<syn>résumé</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>essence</syn>
			<syn>summing-up</syn>
			<syn>digest</syn>
			<syn>epitome</syn>
			<syn>rundown</syn>
			<syn>condensation</syn>
			<syn>compendium</syn>
			<syn>synopsis</syn>
			<syn>précis</syn>
			<syn>recapitulation</syn>
			<syn>review</syn>
			<syn>abridgment</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>draw</syn>
			<syn>pull</syn>
			<syn>remove</syn>
			<syn>separate</syn>
			<syn>withdraw</syn>
			<syn>isolate</syn>
			<syn>pull out</syn>
			<syn>take out</syn>
			<syn>take away</syn>
			<syn>detach</syn>
			<syn>dissociate</syn>
			<syn>pluck out</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summarize</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>shorten</syn>
			<syn>condense</syn>
			<syn>abbreviate</syn>
			<syn>epitomize</syn>
			<syn>abridge</syn>
			<syn>précis</syn>
			<syn>synopsize</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>real</ant>
			<ant>material</ant>
			<ant>specific</ant>
			<ant>actual</ant>
			<ant>concrete</ant>
			<ant>definite</ant>
			<ant>factual</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>expansion</ant>
			<ant>enlargement</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>add</ant>
			<ant>inject</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>barbarian</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>barbarian</title>
		<eng-def>
			someone who behaves in a way that shows they are not well educated and do not care about the feelings of others
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>barbar, acýmasýz, vahþi, zalim kimse</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>That barbarian has dishonored you and my family!</sentence>
		<sentence>"The barbarian can read," he assessed.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She had forgotten he was a barbarian like the others after all he'd done to save her.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He is a barbarian to others and they to him, since they cannot understand what is spoken by him.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			On the decline of the Roman empire Vindobona became the prey of successive barbarian invaders.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			During this period the revolt of the African prince Gildo was suppressed (398); Italy was successfully defended against Alaric, who was defeated at Pollentia (402) and Verona (403); and the barbarian hordes under the Goth Radagaisus were destroyed (406).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The barbarian flung Taran into the darkness.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The green-eyed barbarian accepted both of the treasures, eyes glowing.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In 1557 the Portuguese were permitted to erect factories on the peninsula, and in 1573 the Chinese built across the isthmus the wall which still cuts off the barbarian from the rest of the island.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It must not be confused with the fanciful barbarian costumes that are so common upon the Attic pots.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Arsacids also were afraid of destroying the wealth and commerce of Seleucia, if they entered it with their large retinue of barbarian officials and soldiers (Strabo xvi.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			394), a barbarian officer in the Roman army, at the end of the 4th century.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The values recognized in the great Hellenistic courts and the Greek world generally imposed their authority upon the dynasties of barbarian origin.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Isthmus and with the over-confidence of a conquering barbarian advanced to the relief of the hard-pressed garrison of Nauplia.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			With the disappearance of the Scythae as an ethnic and political entity, the name of Scythia gives place in its original seat to that of Sarmatia, and is artificially applied by geographers, on the one hand, to the Dobrudzha, the lesser Scythia of Strabo, where it remained in official use until Byzantine times; on the other, to the unknown regions of northern Asia, the Eastern Scythia of Strabo, the "Scythia intra et extra Imaum" of Ptolemy; but throughout classical literature Scythia generally meant all regions to the north and north-east of the Black Sea, and a Scythian (Scythes) any barbarian coming from those parts.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Antigonid and Seleucid courts had much valuable material at hand for their armies in the barbarian races under their sway.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The remaining history of the dynasty is a wretched story of the struggle of different claimants, while the different factors of the kingdom, the cities and barbarian races, more and more assert their independence.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The custom, indeed, so far from dying out, was adopted by the barbarian conquerors and spread among the Christian Goths in Spain, Franks in Gaul, Alemanni in Germany, and Anglo-Saxons in Britain.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The barbarian law of the Burgundians shows strong traces of Roman influence.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Destroyed by barbarian invaders in the 7th century the town recovered its importance only in comparatively modern times.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>savage</definition>
		<definition>lout</definition>
		<definition>uncivilized</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>savage</syn>
			<syn>monster</syn>
			<syn>beast</syn>
			<syn>brute</syn>
			<syn>yahoo</syn>
			<syn>swine</syn>
			<syn>ogre</syn>
			<syn>sadist</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>lout</syn>
			<syn>hooligan</syn>
			<syn>illiterate</syn>
			<syn>vandal</syn>
			<syn>bigot</syn>
			<syn>philistine</syn>
			<syn>ned</syn>
			<syn>hoon</syn>
			<syn>cougan</syn>
			<syn>scozza</syn>
			<syn>bogan</syn>
			<syn>ruffian</syn>
			<syn>ignoramus</syn>
			<syn>boor</syn>
			<syn>lowbrow</syn>
			<syn>vulgarian</syn>
			<syn>boot boy</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>uncivilized</syn>
			<syn>wild</syn>
			<syn>rough</syn>
			<syn>savage</syn>
			<syn>crude</syn>
			<syn>primitive</syn>
			<syn>vulgar</syn>
			<syn>illiterate</syn>
			<syn>barbaric</syn>
			<syn>philistine</syn>
			<syn>uneducated</syn>
			<syn>unsophisticated</syn>
			<syn>barbarous</syn>
			<syn>boorish</syn>
			<syn>uncouth</syn>
			<syn>uncultivated</syn>
			<syn>lowbrow</syn>
			<syn>uncultured</syn>
			<syn>unmannered</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>cultured</ant>
			<ant>civil</ant>
			<ant>sophisticated</ant>
			<ant>refined</ant>
			<ant>civilized</ant>
			<ant>genteel</ant>
			<ant>urbane</ant>
			<ant>highbrow</ant>
			<ant>well-mannered</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bear</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to accept someone or something unpleasant</eng-def>
		<tr-def>tahammül etmek, kaldýrmak, dayanmak, katlanmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She couldn't bear the thought of him suffering.</ex>
			<ex>I like her, but I can't bear her friends.</ex>
			<ex>How can you bear to watch?</ex>
			<ex>The pain was too much to bear.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear a resemblance/relation, etc to sb/sth</title>
		<eng-def>to be similar to someone or something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>benzemek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He bears a striking resemblance to his father.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to carry something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>taþýmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He came in, bearing a tray of drinks.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to support the weight of something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>çekmek, götürmek, kaldýrmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>I don't think that chair will bear his weight.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear the responsibility/cost, etc</title>
		<eng-def>
			to accept that you are responsible for something, you should pay for something, etc
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>sorumluluðu üstlenmek, maliyetine katlanmak, sonucuna razý olmak</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				He must bear some responsibility for the appalling conditions in the prison.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to continue to have a bad feeling towards someone</eng-def>
		<tr-def>çekmek, katlanmak, tahammül etmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				They were rude to her in the past, but she's not the kind of woman who bears grudges (= continues to be angry).
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to give birth to a child</eng-def>
		<tr-def>doðurmak, dünyaya getirmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She has been told that she will never bear children.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear</title>
		<eng-def>to have or show a particular name, picture, or symbol</eng-def>
		<tr-def>hususi bir isim, resim veya sembolü olmak, göstermek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>The shop bore his family name.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>bear left/right</title>
		<eng-def>to turn left or right</eng-def>
		<tr-def>sola/saða dönmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Bear right at the next set of traffic lights.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>I could not bear to see her punished.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It wasn't the first time she had seen a bear track, but it was the first time she had seen one that fresh.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Finally Katie could bear the silence no longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>Bear with me a little longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>Finally she could bear the suspense no longer.</sentence>
		<sentence>I can't bear it!</sentence>
		<sentence>I can't bear those old men!</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bear stopped and stared at him, but made no move to run away.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			If the company pollutes, it should bear the cost of that pollution.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			When she heard this Sonya blushed so that tears came into her eyes and, unable to bear the looks turned upon her, ran away into the dancing hall, whirled round it at full speed with her dress puffed out like a balloon, and, flushed and smiling, plumped down on the floor.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The bear lifted her nose, testing the breeze.</sentence>
		<sentence>Alex fired twice more and the bear dropped to the ground.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He seemed unable to bear the sight of tears and was ready to cry himself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>What was it she had heard about bear attacks?</sentence>
		<sentence>He could not bear to see her grief.</sentence>
		<sentence>When the bear continued toward him, he fired.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But go with the firm intention of killing your man as quickly and surely as possible, and then all will be right, as our bear huntsman at Kostroma used to tell me.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The third time that he thrust out the weapon there was a loud roar and a fall, and suddenly at his feet appeared the form of a great red bear, which was nearly as big as the horse and much stronger and fiercer.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			And there was the bear swimming about with the policeman on his back!
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She was sure he would speak soft, tender words to her such as her father had uttered before his death, and that she would not be able to bear it and would burst into sobs in his presence.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>carry</definition>
		<definition>hold</definition>
		<definition>support</definition>
		<definition>display</definition>
		<definition>suffer</definition>
		<definition>bring yourself to</definition>
		<definition>take on</definition>
		<definition>produce</definition>
		<definition>earn</definition>
		<definition>give birth to</definition>
		<definition>exhibit</definition>
		<definition>conduct</definition>
		<definition>turn</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>take</syn>
			<syn>move</syn>
			<syn>bring</syn>
			<syn>lift</syn>
			<syn>transfer</syn>
			<syn>transport</syn>
			<syn>haul</syn>
			<syn>transmit</syn>
			<syn>convey</syn>
			<syn>relay</syn>
			<syn>tote</syn>
			<syn>hump</syn>
			<syn>lug</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>pack</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>shoulder</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>hold up</syn>
			<syn>keep up</syn>
			<syn>uphold</syn>
			<syn>withstand</syn>
			<syn>bear up under</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>display</syn>
			<syn>have</syn>
			<syn>show</syn>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>possess</syn>
			<syn>exhibit</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>suffer</syn>
			<syn>feel</syn>
			<syn>experience</syn>
			<syn>go through</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>stomach</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>undergo</syn>
			<syn>admit</syn>
			<syn>brook</syn>
			<syn>hack</syn>
			<syn>abide</syn>
			<syn>put up with</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>allow</syn>
			<syn>accept</syn>
			<syn>permit</syn>
			<syn>endure</syn>
			<syn>tolerate</syn>
			<syn>hack</syn>
			<syn>abide</syn>
			<syn>be doing with</syn>
			<syn>countenance</syn>
			<syn>bring yourself to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>take on</syn>
			<syn>support</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>accept</syn>
			<syn>shoulder</syn>
			<syn>sustain</syn>
			<syn>absorb</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>produce</syn>
			<syn>give</syn>
			<syn>provide</syn>
			<syn>develop</syn>
			<syn>generate</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>bring forth</syn>
			<syn>give forth</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>earn</syn>
			<syn>make</syn>
			<syn>get</syn>
			<syn>receive</syn>
			<syn>gain</syn>
			<syn>net</syn>
			<syn>collect</syn>
			<syn>realize</syn>
			<syn>obtain</syn>
			<syn>yield</syn>
			<syn>bring in</syn>
			<syn>gross</syn>
			<syn>reap</syn>
			<syn>procure</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>produce</syn>
			<syn>deliver</syn>
			<syn>breed</syn>
			<syn>beget</syn>
			<syn>give birth to</syn>
			<syn>bring forth</syn>
			<syn>be delivered of</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>exhibit</syn>
			<syn>hold</syn>
			<syn>maintain</syn>
			<syn>entertain</syn>
			<syn>harbour</syn>
			<syn>cherish</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>conduct</syn>
			<syn>carry</syn>
			<syn>move</syn>
			<syn>deport</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>turn</syn>
			<syn>tack</syn>
			<syn>veer</syn>
			<syn>swerve</syn>
			<syn>shift</syn>
			<syn>sheer</syn>
			<syn>change direction</syn>
			<syn>change course</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>drop</ant>
			<ant>shed</ant>
			<ant>put down</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>drop</ant>
			<ant>give up</ant>
			<ant>abandon</ant>
			<ant>relinquish</ant>
			<ant>discontinue</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>campaign</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>campaign</title>
		<eng-def>
			a series of organized activities or events intended to achieve a result
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>kampanya, düzenlenen bir dizi faaliyetler bütünü</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an advertising/election campaign</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>campaign</title>
		<eng-def>a series of military attacks</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir dizi askeri saldýrý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bombing campaign</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			If I'm going to be your campaign manager, leave the business to me.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>I'd better get my campaign manager cracking.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			By the end of the four-month campaign, the White House would receive two million dimes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Did you take part in the campaign? he asked.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Six ladies, all carrying campaign signs, formed an honor guard around the vehicle.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			During his campaign and his time in office, the extent of the effect of his polio was kept from the public, but the fact he had the disease was commonly known.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The old prince and his son seemed to have changed roles since the campaign of 1805.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He accomplished a successful campaign in 1868 against Bokhara, capturing Samarkand and gradually subjugating the whole country.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			During the campaign he met his wife, Anita, who became his inseparable companion and mother of three children, Anita, Ricciotti and Menotti.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Then followed in 1875 the campaign against Khokand, in which Kaufmann defeated the khan, Nasr-ed-din.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Dean had blanked his campaign for sheriff from his mind, but now it returned with a headache fury.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Martha bounced around, thrilled to be back in the routine, and joined Fred in passing out more campaign literature.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			1g the German King Lothair, whom he induced to undertake a campaign against Anacletus.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The actions of Napoleon and Alexander, on whose words the event seemed to hang, were as little voluntary as the actions of any soldier who was drawn into the campaign by lot or by conscription.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He then makes his Persian expedition; the Indian campaign gives occasion for descriptions of all kinds of wonders.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There followed a campaign against the idols whose temples and books were destroyed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The campaign of Mons.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"But still this does not mean that the campaign is over," said Prince Andrew.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			had succeeded in forming a new union of royalists and presbyterians, and another campaign became inevitable.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Louis took an active part in the campaign and fought heroically at Jarnac and Moncontour.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>drive</definition>
		<definition>operation</definition>
		<definition>crusade</definition>
		<definition>canvass</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>drive</syn>
			<syn>appeal</syn>
			<syn>movement</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>offensive</syn>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>operation</syn>
			<syn>drive</syn>
			<syn>attack</syn>
			<syn>movement</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>offensive</syn>
			<syn>expedition</syn>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
			<syn>jihad</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>crusade</syn>
			<syn>press</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>encourage</syn>
			<syn>urge</syn>
			<syn>boost</syn>
			<syn>petition</syn>
			<syn>back</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>canvass</syn>
			<syn>electioneer</syn>
			<syn>solicit votes</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>bias</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>bias</title>
		<eng-def>
			a situation in which you support or oppose someone or something in an unfair way because you are influenced by your personal opinions
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>önyargý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a bias towards/against private education</ex>
			<ex>
				The news channel has been accused of bias in favour of the government.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>His natural bias was to respect things as they were.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This document provides guidance on the stages in scheme development at which optimism bias can be reduced.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The townspeople show a bias in favour of French habits and fashions.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To illustrate the self-serving bias with regard to success, I will draw on my own experiences.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His natural parts were excellent; and a strong bias in the direction of abstract thought, and mathematics in particular, was noticeable at an early date.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This bias is reflected in the maxim that "correction should precede interpretation," which is no more than a half-truth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It gives copious details, and, as he had access to the correspondence and official documents of the Spanish leaders, it is, although necessarily possessing bias, the fullest and most authentic record existing of the events it relates.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sovereign as compared with her ministers has, because she is the sovereign, the advantage of long experience, wide survey, elevated position and entire disconnexion from the bias of party.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its author, with a considerable mathematical and mechanical bias, reckoned entirely with the quantity, not with the quality of his units, and relied almost implicitly upon his formulae.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			That phrase accurately describes the prevalent bias of its author's mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Lotze was a man of considerable attainments in special science; perhaps he reveals here the bias of the scientific mind, and possibly even its limitations.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He adhered henceforth to the army party, but with a constant bias in favour of the king.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Another side is the recurring exhibition of the fact that these witnesses were persecuted only by those whose action should create no bias against the persecuted.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The cause of medical materialism is the natural bias of physicians towards explaining the health and disease of mind by the health and disease of body.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But the Christian bias is sure to make theologians, who borrow a doctrine of the Absolute, interpret it in a Christian sense; hence we may consider it something of an accident that even an Augustine fails exactly to put the argument in form.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			All that Hauch wrote is marked by great qualities, and by distinction; he had a native bias towards the mystical, which, however, he learned to keep in abeyance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bias of modern practice, in short, is towards milder methods, not only in treatment, but in those anticipatory processes which may render imprisonment unnecessary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Despite the almost inevitable US bias, it is still worth a visit.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			One of them seeing Bias without anything, advised him to follow the example of the rest.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>codon bias.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>prejudice</definition>
		<definition>slant</definition>
		<definition>influence</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>leaning</syn>
			<syn>bent</syn>
			<syn>tendency</syn>
			<syn>inclination</syn>
			<syn>penchant</syn>
			<syn>intolerance</syn>
			<syn>bigotry</syn>
			<syn>propensity</syn>
			<syn>favouritism</syn>
			<syn>predisposition</syn>
			<syn>nepotism</syn>
			<syn>unfairness</syn>
			<syn>predilection</syn>
			<syn>proclivity</syn>
			<syn>partiality</syn>
			<syn>narrow-mindedness</syn>
			<syn>proneness</syn>
			<syn>one-sidedness</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>cross</syn>
			<syn>angle</syn>
			<syn>diagonal line</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>influence</syn>
			<syn>colour</syn>
			<syn>weight</syn>
			<syn>prejudice</syn>
			<syn>distort</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>warp</syn>
			<syn>slant</syn>
			<syn>predispose</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>equity</ant>
			<ant>equality</ant>
			<ant>fairness</ant>
			<ant>neutrality</ant>
			<ant>objectivity</ant>
			<ant>impartiality</ant>
			<ant>open-mindedness</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>consistent</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>consistent</title>
		<eng-def>always behaving or happening in a similar, usually positive, way</eng-def>
		<tr-def>tutarlï¿½, istikrarlï¿½</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>consistent effort/improvement</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>consistent with sth</title>
		<eng-def>
			having the same principles as something else, or agreeing with other facts
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>birï¿½eyle tutarlï¿½/uyum iï¿½inde/baï¿½daï¿½ï¿½k olan</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				His account of events is entirely consistent with the video evidence.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Her speed was consistent, her destination clear.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This viewpoint seems reasonable because it is largely consistent with our everyday experience of life.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Darian took them to an area where he'd felt a consistent, high level of Other activity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But guilt of that sort would hardly be consistent with his character as it appears in those early days.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In Mexico the national government is carrying out a consistent policy of developing its railway lines.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>If you want to show expertise, consistent practice is vital.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is consistent with all we know of the past, which is progress and prosperity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What remains to be done is, not to explain how such a world manages to be what it is, nor how we came to form these notions, but merely this - to expel from the circle and totality of our conceptions those abstract notions which are inconsistent and jarring, or to remodel and define them so that they may constitute a consistent and harmonious view.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is a consistent policy of harbouring inconsistencies in the same mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>89), is not consistent with history.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			54) If we conceive God as personal, and His will as related to the course of nature analogously to the relation of the human will to the human body, then the laws of nature may be regarded as habits of the divine activity, and miracles as unusual acts which, while consistent with the divine character, mark a new stage in the fulfilment of the purpose of God.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The compactness of the series of rational numbers is consistent with quasi-gaps in it - that is, with the possible absence of limits to classes in it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But as you are a philosopher, be a consistent one, look at the other side of the question and you will see that your duty, on the contrary, is to take care of yourself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In accordance with the consistent policy of inclusion and toleration by which the whole of his official life was characterized, he induced the council to call the assembly of notables, which met at Fontainebleau in August 1560 and agreed that the States General should be summoned, all proceedings against heretics being meanwhile suppressed, pending the reformation of the church by a general or national council.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Experimental conditions were thoroughly worked out; the necessity of working with hot or cold solutions was clearly emphasized; and the employment of small quantities of substances instead of the large amounts recommended by Klaproth was shown by him to give more consistent results.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There is some reason to hope that the day of these misconceptions is passed; although there is also some reason to fear that on other grounds the present era may be known to posterity as an era of instrumentation comparable, in its gorgeous chaos of experiment and its lack of consistent ideas of harmony and form, only to the monodic period at the beginning of the 17th century, in which no one had ears for anything but experiments in harmonic colour.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In fact, he was only consistent in his inconsistency (semper in omnibus varies).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Please continue to knead the dough by hand until it is mixed to a consistent texture.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Guelph party was held together with a less tight hand even in cities so consistent as Florence.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The relation between the b.h.p. and the torque on the driving-axle is 55 o B.H.P. =Tu., (9) It is usual with steam locomotives to regard the resistance R as including the frictional resistances between the cylinders and the driving-axle, so that the rate at which energy is expended in moving the train is expressed either by the product RV, or by the value of the indicated horse-power, the relation between them being 55 0 I.H.P. =RV (Io) or in terms of the torque 55 0 I.H.P.X€=RVe=TW (II) The individual factors of the product RV may have any value consistent with equation (to) and with certain practical conditions, so that for a given value of the I.H.P. R must decrease if V increases.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>steady</definition>
		<definition>compatible</definition>
		<definition>coherent</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>steady</syn>
			<syn>even</syn>
			<syn>regular</syn>
			<syn>stable</syn>
			<syn>constant</syn>
			<syn>persistent</syn>
			<syn>dependable</syn>
			<syn>unchanging</syn>
			<syn>undeviating</syn>
			<syn>true to type</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>compatible</syn>
			<syn>agreeing</syn>
			<syn>harmonious</syn>
			<syn>consonant</syn>
			<syn>congruent</syn>
			<syn>congruous</syn>
			<syn>accordant</syn>
			<syn>in keeping</syn>
			<syn>in harmony</syn>
			<syn>in accord</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>coherent</syn>
			<syn>logical</syn>
			<syn>compatible</syn>
			<syn>harmonious</syn>
			<syn>consonant</syn>
			<syn>all of a piece</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>changing</ant>
			<ant>irregular</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>erratic</ant>
			<ant>deviating</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>contrary</ant>
			<ant>contradictory</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>incompatible</ant>
			<ant>incongruous</ant>
			<ant>discordant</ant>
			<ant>inharmonious</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>contradictory</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>incompatible</ant>
			<ant>illogical</ant>
			<ant>incoherent</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>cultivate</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>cultivate</title>
		<eng-def>to prepare land and grow crops on it</eng-def>
		<tr-def>topraðý iþlemek, ekip biçmek, sürüp ekmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>This shrub is cultivated in Europe as a herb used in cooking.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>cultivate</title>
		<eng-def>to try to develop or improve something</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir þeyi geliþtirmek, ilerletmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She has cultivated an image as a tough negotiator.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Why anyone would cultivate that nasty habit is a mystery to me.</sentence>
		<sentence>Some live in settled communities and roughly cultivate the soil.</sentence>
		<sentence>They are very easy to cultivate and do not require lifting.</sentence>
		<sentence>The insects cultivate their fungus, weeding out.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Crispi was prepared to cultivate good relations with France, but refused to yield to pressure or to submit to dicta - tion; and in this attitude he was firmly supported by the bulk of his fellow-countrymen.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Nearly all the land is in the hands of peasant proprietors, who cultivate sweet potatoes, peas, beans, corn, &c., and rear sheep and goats.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The Piojes live in permanent communities and cultivate the soil.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is not desirable to cultivate a respect for the law, so much as for the right.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Cultivate poverty like a garden herb, like sage.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The mountaineers breed some cattle and sheep, and cultivate small fields on the mountain-sides.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He must be in touch with the actual life of the community he is studying, and cultivate " that openness and alertness of the mind, that sensitiveness of the judgment, which can rapidly grasp the significance of at first sight unrelated discoveries or events."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Great part is mountainous, but some very fertile valleys exist, to cultivate which 2000 yoke of oxen are employed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			ager, field, and colere, to cultivate), the science, art and industry of utilizing the soil so as to produce the means of human subsistence, embracing in its widest sense the rearing of live-stock as well as the raising of crops.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He took a foremost part in almost every good work in his diocese, social or educational, political or religious; while he found time also to cultivate friendly relations with thinking men and women of all schools, and to help all and sundry who came to him for advice and assistance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Not till the 13th of February were the miserable remnants of the population permitted to rebuild their houses and cultivate their fields once more.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			If the debtor did not cultivate the field himself he had to pay for the cultivation, but if the cultivation was already finished he must harvest it himself and pay his debt from the crop. If the cultivator did not get a crop this would not cancel his contract.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			These cultivate gambier and pepper successfully in Bintang, and there is a considerable trade in wood.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the moist bottom-lands along the rivers it is the custom to throw the soil up in high beds with the plough, and then to cultivate them deep. This is the more common method of drainage, but it is expensive, as it has to be renewed every few years.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			While their neighbours, the Malays, Papuans and Polynesians, all cultivate the soil, and build substantial huts and houses, the Australian natives do neither.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Hansen set himself the task of studying the properties of the varieties of yeast, and to do this he had to cultivate each variety in a pure state.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>farm</definition>
		<definition>develop</definition>
		<definition>court</definition>
		<definition>foster</definition>
		<definition>improve</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>farm</syn>
			<syn>work</syn>
			<syn>plant</syn>
			<syn>tend</syn>
			<syn>till</syn>
			<syn>harvest</syn>
			<syn>plough</syn>
			<syn>bring under cultivation</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>develop</syn>
			<syn>establish</syn>
			<syn>acquire</syn>
			<syn>foster</syn>
			<syn>pursue</syn>
			<syn>devote yourself to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>court</syn>
			<syn>seek out</syn>
			<syn>run after</syn>
			<syn>butter up</syn>
			<syn>associate with</syn>
			<syn>consort with</syn>
			<syn>dance attendance upon</syn>
			<syn>seek someone's company or friendship</syn>
			<syn>take trouble or pains with</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>foster</syn>
			<syn>further</syn>
			<syn>forward</syn>
			<syn>encourage</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>improve</syn>
			<syn>better</syn>
			<syn>train</syn>
			<syn>discipline</syn>
			<syn>polish</syn>
			<syn>refine</syn>
			<syn>elevate</syn>
			<syn>enrich</syn>
			<syn>civilize</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>comprise</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>comprise</title>
		<eng-def>to consist of particular parts or members</eng-def>
		<tr-def>... den/dan oluþmak/meydana gelmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				The orchestra was comprised of amateur and professional musicians.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>comprise</title>
		<eng-def>to form part of something, especially a larger group</eng-def>
		<tr-def>oluþturmak, meydana getirmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Women comprise 15% of the police force.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>How many comprise the group?</sentence>
		<sentence>The population is known to comprise a mixture of races.</sentence>
		<sentence>Can your notes comprise a user manual?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The manufactures comprise sheet-iron, boilers, zinc, brick and tiles, paraffin, petroleum, soap and candles.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			That element will comprise less than 1% of total litter and pollution.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This subject will comprise approximately 50% of the course content.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>These comprise the Welsh portion of the MSS.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The conformation of the mountain districts, which comprise all the southern districts of Badakshan and the northern hills.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its industrial establishments comprise tobacco, yarn, thread, linen and woollen cloth manufactories, bleaching and dyeing works, breweries and oil and flour mills.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The military and historical works comprise precis of the wars of Julius Caesar, Turenne and Frederick the Great.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Birds of prey comprise several species of hawks and owls, and a few eagles.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Those of the first class, which comprise rather less than half the entire system, have a minimum depth of 64 ft., with locks 126 ft.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The indirect taxes comprise the charges on registration; stamps; customs; and a group of taxes specially described as indirect taxes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The industrial establishments comprise reduction works, saw-mills and flour-mills, one of the latter being the largest in Canada.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			One of the results of these investigations was to extend the meaning of the word mechanism, and comprise under it all laws which obtain in the phenomenal world, not excepting the phenomena of life and mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			We have seen that the name of Italy was originally applied only to the southernmost part of the peninsula, and was only gradually extended so as to comprise the central regions, such as Latium and Campania, which were designated by writers as late as Thucydides and Aristotle as in Opicia.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Subdivisions may be, and often are, named according to the particular duties to which they are assigned, as la police politique, police des mceurs, police sanitaire, &c. The officers of the judicial police comprise the juge de paix (equivalent to the English police magistrate), the maire, the commissaire de police, the gendarmerie and, in rural districts, the gardes champtres and the gardes forestiers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Turkey's Arabian possessions comprise, besides El-Hasa on the Persian Gulf, the low-lying, hot and insalubrious Tehama and the south-western highlands (vilayets of Hejaz and Yemen) stretching continuously along the east side of the Red Sea, and including the two holy cities of Mecca and Medina.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			These two great divisions are moreover of unequal value, for the Cryptogams comprise several groups differing from each other by characters as marked as those which separate some of them from the Phanerogams. The following groups or sub-kingdoms are those which are now generally recognized:
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The ores found here comprise silver-free galena, sulphate of zinc and calamine.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>be composed of</definition>
		<definition>make up</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>include</syn>
			<syn>contain</syn>
			<syn>consist of</syn>
			<syn>take in</syn>
			<syn>embrace</syn>
			<syn>encompass</syn>
			<syn>comprehend</syn>
			<syn>be composed of</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>make up</syn>
			<syn>form</syn>
			<syn>constitute</syn>
			<syn>compose</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>consistent</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>consistent</title>
		<eng-def>always behaving or happening in a similar, usually positive, way</eng-def>
		<tr-def>tutarlý, istikrarlý</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>consistent effort/improvement</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>consistent with sth</title>
		<eng-def>
			having the same principles as something else, or agreeing with other facts
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>birþeyle tutarlý/uyum içinde/baðdaþýk olan</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				His account of events is entirely consistent with the video evidence.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Her speed was consistent, her destination clear.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This viewpoint seems reasonable because it is largely consistent with our everyday experience of life.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Darian took them to an area where he'd felt a consistent, high level of Other activity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But guilt of that sort would hardly be consistent with his character as it appears in those early days.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In Mexico the national government is carrying out a consistent policy of developing its railway lines.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>If you want to show expertise, consistent practice is vital.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is consistent with all we know of the past, which is progress and prosperity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What remains to be done is, not to explain how such a world manages to be what it is, nor how we came to form these notions, but merely this - to expel from the circle and totality of our conceptions those abstract notions which are inconsistent and jarring, or to remodel and define them so that they may constitute a consistent and harmonious view.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is a consistent policy of harbouring inconsistencies in the same mind.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>89), is not consistent with history.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			54) If we conceive God as personal, and His will as related to the course of nature analogously to the relation of the human will to the human body, then the laws of nature may be regarded as habits of the divine activity, and miracles as unusual acts which, while consistent with the divine character, mark a new stage in the fulfilment of the purpose of God.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The compactness of the series of rational numbers is consistent with quasi-gaps in it - that is, with the possible absence of limits to classes in it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But as you are a philosopher, be a consistent one, look at the other side of the question and you will see that your duty, on the contrary, is to take care of yourself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In accordance with the consistent policy of inclusion and toleration by which the whole of his official life was characterized, he induced the council to call the assembly of notables, which met at Fontainebleau in August 1560 and agreed that the States General should be summoned, all proceedings against heretics being meanwhile suppressed, pending the reformation of the church by a general or national council.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Experimental conditions were thoroughly worked out; the necessity of working with hot or cold solutions was clearly emphasized; and the employment of small quantities of substances instead of the large amounts recommended by Klaproth was shown by him to give more consistent results.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There is some reason to hope that the day of these misconceptions is passed; although there is also some reason to fear that on other grounds the present era may be known to posterity as an era of instrumentation comparable, in its gorgeous chaos of experiment and its lack of consistent ideas of harmony and form, only to the monodic period at the beginning of the 17th century, in which no one had ears for anything but experiments in harmonic colour.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In fact, he was only consistent in his inconsistency (semper in omnibus varies).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Please continue to knead the dough by hand until it is mixed to a consistent texture.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Guelph party was held together with a less tight hand even in cities so consistent as Florence.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The relation between the b.h.p. and the torque on the driving-axle is 55 o B.H.P. =Tu., (9) It is usual with steam locomotives to regard the resistance R as including the frictional resistances between the cylinders and the driving-axle, so that the rate at which energy is expended in moving the train is expressed either by the product RV, or by the value of the indicated horse-power, the relation between them being 55 0 I.H.P. =RV (Io) or in terms of the torque 55 0 I.H.P.X€=RVe=TW (II) The individual factors of the product RV may have any value consistent with equation (to) and with certain practical conditions, so that for a given value of the I.H.P. R must decrease if V increases.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>steady</definition>
		<definition>compatible</definition>
		<definition>coherent</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>steady</syn>
			<syn>even</syn>
			<syn>regular</syn>
			<syn>stable</syn>
			<syn>constant</syn>
			<syn>persistent</syn>
			<syn>dependable</syn>
			<syn>unchanging</syn>
			<syn>undeviating</syn>
			<syn>true to type</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>compatible</syn>
			<syn>agreeing</syn>
			<syn>harmonious</syn>
			<syn>consonant</syn>
			<syn>congruent</syn>
			<syn>congruous</syn>
			<syn>accordant</syn>
			<syn>in keeping</syn>
			<syn>in harmony</syn>
			<syn>in accord</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>coherent</syn>
			<syn>logical</syn>
			<syn>compatible</syn>
			<syn>harmonious</syn>
			<syn>consonant</syn>
			<syn>all of a piece</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>changing</ant>
			<ant>irregular</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>erratic</ant>
			<ant>deviating</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>contrary</ant>
			<ant>contradictory</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>incompatible</ant>
			<ant>incongruous</ant>
			<ant>discordant</ant>
			<ant>inharmonious</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>contradictory</ant>
			<ant>inconsistent</ant>
			<ant>incompatible</ant>
			<ant>illogical</ant>
			<ant>incoherent</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>abstract</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>relating to ideas and not real things</eng-def>
		<tr-def>soyut</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an abstract concept</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>abstract</title>
		<eng-def>
			Abstract art involves shapes and colours and not images of real things or people.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>
			gerï¿½ek nesne ve kiï¿½ilerin imgelerinden ï¿½ok renk ve ï¿½ekilleri iï¿½eren soyut sanat
		</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			They had no abstract ideas; in their minds all was concrete, visible and tangible.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>His abstract submission met the deadline.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Choose five abstract nouns relating to recent conversational themes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Do you have an abstract of a paper or presentation you would like to give?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He presented abstract concepts with empirical data.</sentence>
		<sentence>Can I have an abstract of the article?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Thus Descartes gave to modern geometry that abstract and general character in which consists its superiority to the geometry of the ancients.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He was searching for an abstract expressionist painting by de Kooning.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Congress (London, 18 95), p. 735 (English Abstract, p. 748).</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It does not appear, however, that a regularly organized or numerous Orphic sect ever existed, nor that Orphism ever became popular; it was too abstract, too full of symbolism.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He asked me how I had taught Helen adjectives and the names of abstract ideas like goodness and happiness.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What remains to be done is, not to explain how such a world manages to be what it is, nor how we came to form these notions, but merely this - to expel from the circle and totality of our conceptions those abstract notions which are inconsistent and jarring, or to remodel and define them so that they may constitute a consistent and harmonious view.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Moreover, the abstract terms stem, leaf, root, &c., are absolutely indispensable; and are continually used in this sense by the most ardent organographers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Abstract expressionism was a New York painting movement of the 1940's with its artistic roots based upon abstract art.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Secondly: from the discrepancy between the pure abstract law of self-consistent reason and the pleasuretinged nature of man, we infer or postulate Immortality.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was evident that Prince Andrew was not interested in such abstract conversation.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the very nature of things, articulation is an unsatisfactory means of education; while the use of the manual alphabet quickens and invigorates mental activity, since through it the deaf child is brought into close contact with the English language, and the highest and most abstract ideas may be conveyed to the mind readily and accurately.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The neuter term brahma is used in the Rigveda both in the abstract sense of "devotion, worship," and in the concrete sense of "devotional rite, prayer, hymn."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The first, De Sancta Trinitate, is addressed to Symmachus (Domino Patri Symmacho), and the result of the short discussion, which is of an abstract nature, and deals partly with the ten categories, is that unity is predicated absolutely, or, in regard to the substance of the Deity, trinity is predicated relatively.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Klebs, Guide to Exhibit of the German Amber Industry at World's Fair (St Louis, 1904); and abstract by G.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>theoretical</definition>
		<definition>symbolic</definition>
		<definition>summary</definition>
		<definition>extract</definition>
		<definition>summarize</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>theoretical</syn>
			<syn>general</syn>
			<syn>academic</syn>
			<syn>intellectual</syn>
			<syn>subtle</syn>
			<syn>profound</syn>
			<syn>philosophical</syn>
			<syn>speculative</syn>
			<syn>unrealistic</syn>
			<syn>conceptual</syn>
			<syn>indefinite</syn>
			<syn>deep</syn>
			<syn>occult</syn>
			<syn>hypothetical</syn>
			<syn>generalized</syn>
			<syn>impractical</syn>
			<syn>arcane</syn>
			<syn>notional</syn>
			<syn>abstruse</syn>
			<syn>recondite</syn>
			<syn>theoretic</syn>
			<syn>conjectural</syn>
			<syn>unpractical</syn>
			<syn>nonconcrete</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>symbolic</syn>
			<syn>figurative</syn>
			<syn>emblematic</syn>
			<syn>impressionistic</syn>
			<syn>non-representational</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summary</syn>
			<syn>rï¿½sumï¿½</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>essence</syn>
			<syn>summing-up</syn>
			<syn>digest</syn>
			<syn>epitome</syn>
			<syn>rundown</syn>
			<syn>condensation</syn>
			<syn>compendium</syn>
			<syn>synopsis</syn>
			<syn>prï¿½cis</syn>
			<syn>recapitulation</syn>
			<syn>review</syn>
			<syn>abridgment</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>extract</syn>
			<syn>draw</syn>
			<syn>pull</syn>
			<syn>remove</syn>
			<syn>separate</syn>
			<syn>withdraw</syn>
			<syn>isolate</syn>
			<syn>pull out</syn>
			<syn>take out</syn>
			<syn>take away</syn>
			<syn>detach</syn>
			<syn>dissociate</syn>
			<syn>pluck out</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>summarize</syn>
			<syn>outline</syn>
			<syn>shorten</syn>
			<syn>condense</syn>
			<syn>abbreviate</syn>
			<syn>epitomize</syn>
			<syn>abridge</syn>
			<syn>prï¿½cis</syn>
			<syn>synopsize</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>real</ant>
			<ant>material</ant>
			<ant>specific</ant>
			<ant>actual</ant>
			<ant>concrete</ant>
			<ant>definite</ant>
			<ant>factual</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>expansion</ant>
			<ant>enlargement</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>add</ant>
			<ant>inject</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>advance</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>in advance</title>
		<eng-def>before a particular time</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ï¿½nceden</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>You need to book your ticket at least 14 days in advance.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>new discoveries and inventions</eng-def>
		<tr-def>yeni keï¿½ifler ve icatlar</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>technological/scientific advances</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>
			a payment given to someone before work has been completed, or before the usual time
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>avans, ï¿½nceden ï¿½denen para, ï¿½deme</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>a movement forward, especially by an army</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ordunun ileri hareketi</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>to develop or progress, or to make something develop or progress</eng-def>
		<tr-def>geliï¿½tirmek, ilerletmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He moved to New York with hopes of advancing his career.</ex>
			<ex>Research has advanced our understanding of the virus.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>to move forward to a new position, especially while fighting</eng-def>
		<tr-def>muharebede yeni bir mevziye doï¿½ru ilerlemek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Rebel soldiers advanced on the capital.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>advance</title>
		<eng-def>happening or ready before an event</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ï¿½nceden olan</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>advance planning/warning</ex>
			<ex>an advance booking</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Consider it an advance until you get the package.</sentence>
		<sentence>In many respects he was far in advance of his age.</sentence>
		<sentence>I gave you advance warning.</sentence>
		<sentence>There's no advance notice except the general area.</sentence>
		<sentence>They were under orders to advance next day.</sentence>
		<sentence>He must stay the victorious advance of the Turks.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The advance made in agricultural industry also is of very great importance.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			We have established that outsourcing, free trade, and technological advance all have the same effect on the system: They lower prices and increase net wealth.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"We shall probably advance," replied Bolkonski, evidently reluctant to say more in the presence of a stranger.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			They all had but one wish: to advance as soon as possible against the enemy under the Emperor's command.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I do not wish to flatter my townsmen, nor to be flattered by them, for that will not advance either of us.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He'd paid in advance for two assignations after he began to suspect there was a traitor in his organization. The second had been for Katie, in case she couldn't be reasoned with.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The first advance came about 74, when what is now Baden was invaded and in part annexed and a road carried from the Roman base on the upper Rhine, Strassburg, to the Danube just above Ulm.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Overtaking the battalions that continued to advance, he stopped the third division and convinced himself that there really were no sharpshooters in front of our columns.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It looks as if the insurance company may be willing to advance some of the life insurance moneyï¿½at least enough to tide us over for a while.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In common with the okapi, giraffes have skin-covered horns on the head, but in these animals, which form the genus Giraffa, these appendages are present in both sexes; and there is often an unpaired one in advance of the pair on the forehead.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Technological advance, however, is not limited in that way.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Jim, who was in advance, saw the last stair before him and stuck his head above the rocky sides of the stairway.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Mr. Mayer did say he was going to talk to them about some sort of advance to hold me over.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The second advance was made by Domitian about A.D.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>progress</definition>
		<definition>accelerate</definition>
		<definition>improve</definition>
		<definition>suggest</definition>
		<definition>lend</definition>
		<definition>promote</definition>
		<definition>down payment</definition>
		<definition>attack</definition>
		<definition>improvement</definition>
		<definition>increase</definition>
		<definition>overtures</definition>
		<definition>prior</definition>
		<definition>expeditionary</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>progress</syn>
			<syn>proceed</syn>
			<syn>go ahead</syn>
			<syn>move up</syn>
			<syn>come forward</syn>
			<syn>go forward</syn>
			<syn>press on</syn>
			<syn>gain ground</syn>
			<syn>make inroads</syn>
			<syn>make headway</syn>
			<syn>make your way</syn>
			<syn>cover ground</syn>
			<syn>make strides</syn>
			<syn>move onward</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>accelerate</syn>
			<syn>speed</syn>
			<syn>promote</syn>
			<syn>step up</syn>
			<syn>hasten</syn>
			<syn>precipitate</syn>
			<syn>quicken</syn>
			<syn>bring forward</syn>
			<syn>push forward</syn>
			<syn>expedite</syn>
			<syn>crack on</syn>
			<syn>hurry (up)</syn>
			<syn>send forward</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>improve</syn>
			<syn>rise</syn>
			<syn>grow</syn>
			<syn>develop</syn>
			<syn>reform</syn>
			<syn>pick up</syn>
			<syn>progress</syn>
			<syn>thrive</syn>
			<syn>upgrade</syn>
			<syn>multiply</syn>
			<syn>prosper</syn>
			<syn>make strides</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>suggest</syn>
			<syn>offer</syn>
			<syn>present</syn>
			<syn>propose</syn>
			<syn>allege</syn>
			<syn>cite</syn>
			<syn>advocate</syn>
			<syn>submit</syn>
			<syn>prescribe</syn>
			<syn>put forward</syn>
			<syn>proffer</syn>
			<syn>adduce</syn>
			<syn>offer as a suggestion</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>lend</syn>
			<syn>loan</syn>
			<syn>accommodate someone with</syn>
			<syn>supply on credit</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>promote</syn>
			<syn>help</syn>
			<syn>further</syn>
			<syn>aid</syn>
			<syn>forward</syn>
			<syn>champion</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>encourage</syn>
			<syn>assist</syn>
			<syn>plug</syn>
			<syn>hasten</syn>
			<syn>patronize</syn>
			<syn>succour</syn>
			<syn>pave the way for</syn>
			<syn>lend support to</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>down payment</syn>
			<syn>credit</syn>
			<syn>fee</syn>
			<syn>deposit</syn>
			<syn>retainer</syn>
			<syn>prepayment</syn>
			<syn>loan</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>attack</syn>
			<syn>charge</syn>
			<syn>strike</syn>
			<syn>rush</syn>
			<syn>assault</syn>
			<syn>raid</syn>
			<syn>invasion</syn>
			<syn>offensive</syn>
			<syn>onslaught</syn>
			<syn>advancement</syn>
			<syn>foray</syn>
			<syn>incursion</syn>
			<syn>forward movement</syn>
			<syn>onward movement</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>improvement</syn>
			<syn>development</syn>
			<syn>gain</syn>
			<syn>growth</syn>
			<syn>breakthrough</syn>
			<syn>advancement</syn>
			<syn>step</syn>
			<syn>headway</syn>
			<syn>inroads</syn>
			<syn>betterment</syn>
			<syn>furtherance</syn>
			<syn>amelioration</syn>
			<syn>forward movement</syn>
			<syn>onward movement</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>increase</syn>
			<syn>rise</syn>
			<syn>development</syn>
			<syn>gain</syn>
			<syn>growth</syn>
			<syn>boost</syn>
			<syn>addition</syn>
			<syn>expansion</syn>
			<syn>extension</syn>
			<syn>enlargement</syn>
			<syn>escalation</syn>
			<syn>upsurge</syn>
			<syn>upturn</syn>
			<syn>increment</syn>
			<syn>intensification</syn>
			<syn>augmentation</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>overtures</syn>
			<syn>moves</syn>
			<syn>offer</syn>
			<syn>approach</syn>
			<syn>proposal</syn>
			<syn>come-on</syn>
			<syn>invitation</syn>
			<syn>proposition</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prior</syn>
			<syn>early</syn>
			<syn>previous</syn>
			<syn>beforehand</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>expeditionary</syn>
			<syn>first</syn>
			<syn>leading</syn>
			<syn>test</syn>
			<syn>forward</syn>
			<syn>in front</syn>
			<syn>preliminary</syn>
			<syn>foremost</syn>
			<syn>exploratory</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>retreat</ant>
			<ant>weaken</ant>
			<ant>diminish</ant>
			<ant>move back</ant>
			<ant>lessen</ant>
			<ant>regress</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>hide</ant>
			<ant>suppress</ant>
			<ant>withhold</ant>
			<ant>hold back</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant></ant>
			<ant></ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>hold back</ant>
			<ant>impede</ant>
			<ant>set back</ant>
			<ant>demote</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>creation</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>creation</title>
		<eng-def>a process in which someone makes something happen or exist</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ortaya konulan ï¿½alï¿½ï¿½ma, kreasyon</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>the creation of a new political party</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>creation</title>
		<eng-def>something that someone has made</eng-def>
		<tr-def>eser, ï¿½alï¿½ï¿½ma, buluï¿½, icat</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>The museum contains some of his best creations.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>creation</title>
		<eng-def>
			in many religions, the process in which God made the universe and everything in it
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>yaratï¿½lï¿½ï¿½, kï¿½inatï¿½n yaratï¿½lï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			Was her position at the office merely the creation of a doting father?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Man is the creation of an all-powerful, all-good, and all-seeing God.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The morning wind forever blows, the poem of creation is uninterrupted; but few are the ears that hear it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>"Sing of the creation," was the answer.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Internet has allowed for the creation of thousands of new ways to give, both time and money.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The principle of energy makes it clear that the light emitted laterally is not a new creation, but only diverted from the main stream.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>It is a creation of the Germans, the site,.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The first mechanism is the creation of things, an old and familiar approach.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			For a short while he was at the head of the new Hessian administration; but his ambition was to share in the creation of a united Germany.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			To the men who fought against the rising truths of physical philosophy, it seemed that if they admitted that truth it would destroy faith in God, in the creation of the firmament, and in the miracle of Joshua the son of Nun.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Knowing this allowed for the creation of a drug called Imatinib, which inhibits this process.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>An image not of her own creation pushed itself into her mind.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			A woman your age ought to be looking for a husband ï¿½ or already married, not chasing all over creation in pants, trying to act like a man.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Among his first acts was the creation of nine French cardinals.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"Go. Await my messenger. Once Rhyn enters the underworld, you will follow him," he said, looking over his creation with satisfaction.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This led to the creation of large libraries all around the worldï¿½and this was a problem.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The older account of the creation in Gen.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Fred asked the question like a learned professor, speculating on a universal problem of time, space and the creation of the universe.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			We have already mentioned the final conception in which Lotze's speculation culminates, that of a personal Deity, Himself the essence of all that merits existence for its own sake, who in the creation and government of a world has voluntarily chosen certain laws and forms through which His ends are to be realized.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The original substance of the world is the materia primo-prima, which is the immediate creation of the Deity.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>universe</definition>
		<definition>invention</definition>
		<definition>making</definition>
		<definition>setting up</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>universe</syn>
			<syn>world</syn>
			<syn>life</syn>
			<syn>nature</syn>
			<syn>cosmos</syn>
			<syn>natural world</syn>
			<syn>living world</syn>
			<syn>all living things</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>invention</syn>
			<syn>production</syn>
			<syn>concept</syn>
			<syn>achievement</syn>
			<syn>brainchild</syn>
			<syn>concoction</syn>
			<syn>handiwork</syn>
			<syn>piï¿½ce de rï¿½sistance</syn>
			<syn>magnum opus</syn>
			<syn>chef-d'oeuvre</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>making</syn>
			<syn>generation</syn>
			<syn>formation</syn>
			<syn>conception</syn>
			<syn>genesis</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>setting up</syn>
			<syn>development</syn>
			<syn>production</syn>
			<syn>institution</syn>
			<syn>foundation</syn>
			<syn>constitution</syn>
			<syn>establishment</syn>
			<syn>formation</syn>
			<syn>inception</syn>
			<syn>laying down</syn>
			<syn>origination</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>corporate</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>corporate</title>
		<eng-def>relating to a large company or group</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bï¿½yï¿½k ï¿½irket veya gruba iliï¿½kin</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>corporate finance</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			He was friendly enough, but no threat to anyone and no corporate climber.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The city coroner is a corporate officer.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is possible that Minehead had a corporate existence during the 15th century, as certain documents executed by the portreeve and burgesses at that date are preserved, but no record of the grant of a charter has been found.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The apothecaries, who were the pharmacists of those days, were not represented by any corporate body, but in the reign of King James I., in 1606, were incorporated with the Company of Grocers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is one of the few examples of free corporate action on the part of the ancient Greek cities, whose centrifugal yearning for independence so often proved fatal to the Hellenic world.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The non-incorporated members are within the municipal jurisdiction of the ports to which they are attached; but the corporate members are as free within their own liberties as the individual ports themselves.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Joseph thinks he's a big corporate executive but he's really only half a step above a clerk.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Port of London Authority, as constituted by the act of 1908, is a body corporate consisting of a chairman, vice-chairman, 17 members elected by payers of dues, wharfingers and owners of river craft, I member elected by wharfingers exclusively, and To members appointed by the following existing bodies - Admiralty (one); Board of Trade (two); London County Council (two from among its own members and two others); City Corporation (one from among its own members and one other); Trinity House (one).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sesqui-centennial of Pittsburgh, elaborately observed in 1908, marked the beginning of a new period of corporate, educational, social and material development.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			On the question of reunion, the ideal of corporate unity was reaffirmed (58).
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The so-called cities (7rbXas) of the TEpioucot answered pretty well to the local plebeian tribes; the difference is that the 7repioLKOC never became a united corporate body like the Roman plebs.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Whether you are for the organic food movement or against it, for genetically modified crops or against them, for corporate farms or seed banks or raw food or anything else, is influenced significantly by your larger view of politics.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The town was corporate from the 16th century until 1886.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The events seem to belong to the histories of the several cities, and examples of corporate action are few and uncertain.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The second part of the act provides that if any person or persons, bodies politic and corporate, for any sum of money, reward, gift, profit or benefit, directly or indirectly, or for or by reason of any promise, agreement, grant, bond, covenant or other assurances.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In these years the Athenian sailors reached a high pitch of training, and by their successes strengthened that corporate pride which had been born at Salamis.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			As the name implies, the ports originally constituting the body were only five in number - Hastings, Romney, Hythe, Dover and Sandwich; but to these were afterwards added the "ancient towns" of Winchelsea and Rye with the same privileges, and a good many other places, both corporate and non-corporate, which, with the title of limb or member, held a subordinate position.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In both states the consent of the Commission is necessary for the issue of corporate securities.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The total losses suffered by private citizens and corporate societies until the advent of Bolshevism is valued at 1,930,000,000 gold rubles; Soviet Russia inflicted losses to the amount of 953,000,000 gold rubles; German occupation and warfare to that of 481,000,000 marks.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Various alterations were subsequently made and now the qualification of electors at the election of the corporate offices of lord mayor, sheriffs, chamberlain and minor offices in Common Hall is that of being a liveryman of a livery company and an enrolled freeman of London.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>collective</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>collective</syn>
			<syn>collaborative</syn>
			<syn>united</syn>
			<syn>shared</syn>
			<syn>allied</syn>
			<syn>joint</syn>
			<syn>combined</syn>
			<syn>pooled</syn>
			<syn>merged</syn>
			<syn>communal</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>ambitious</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>ambitious</title>
		<eng-def>wanting to be successful or powerful</eng-def>
		<tr-def>hï¿½rslï¿½, azimli</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>an ambitious young lawyer</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>ambitious</title>
		<eng-def>
			An ambitious plan will need a lot of work and will be difficult to achieve.
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>hï¿½rs, azim, gayret gerektiren</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>This is our most ambitious project so far.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>She was ambitious, driven by her need for power.</sentence>
		<sentence>I make sure ambitious people like you don't mess up this world.</sentence>
		<sentence>Truly, we are deep thinkers, we are ambitious spirits!</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The themes of all his more ambitious poems can be traced to Chaucerian sources.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			For a time Bela was equally fortunate in the north-west, where the ambitious and enterprising Piemyslidae had erected a new Bohemian empire which absorbed the territories of the old Babenbergers and was very menacing to Hungary.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Tim had been prepared for this day by two generations of ambitious men who intended to see someone of their bloodline in the seat of power.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The best proof of his not being ambitious of such a doubtful piece of preferment is that he made no attempt to get himself made king, regent or lieutenant-general of the kingdom at the time of the flight to Varennes in June 1791.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Soter (reigned 162-150) was a strong and ambitious ruler.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			We may religion regard his ambitious programme as the last logical development of idealism and indeed of philosophy itself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She was the daughter of Gratien Phlipon, a Paris engraver, who was ambitious, speculative and nearly always poor.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Because military accomplishments were one way to do that, the military attracted the most ambitious young men eager to prove themselvesï¿½and "proving themselves" meant battle.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Strong, talented and ambitious, Gaveston gained great influence over young Edward, and early in 1307 he was banished from England by the king; but he returned after the death of Edward I.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Capponi resigned in October 1848, and Leopold reluctantly consented to a democratic ministry led by Guerrazzi and Montanelli, the former a very ambitious and unscrupulous man, the latter honest but fantastic. Following the Roman example, a constituent assembly was demanded to vote on union with Rome and eventually with the rest of Italy.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The Nuremberg globe is a work of a more ambitious order.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Thus, appeared the grand-prince of Suzdal or Vladimir, of Tver,, of Ryazan and of Moscow - all irreconcilable rivals with little or no feeling of blood-relationship. The more ambitious and powerful among them aspired not to succeed but to subdue the others and to take possession of their territory, and the armed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			On hearing of the death of the poet Dakiki, he conceived the ambitious design of himself carrying out the work which the latter had only just commenced; and, although he had not then any introduction to the court, he contrived, thanks to one of his friends, Mahommed Lashkari, to procure a copy of the Dihkan Danishwer's collection, and at the age of thirty-six commenced his great undertaking.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>His idea is equal parts ambitious and audacious.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The boy's talents justified the ambitious hopes which his parents entertained of his future.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			As the Muscovite and the Lithuano-Polish princes were equally ambitious and equally anxious to widen their borders, they naturally came into conflict.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			For the ambitious Moscow princes many of the Byzantine ideas were very acceptable.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>enterprising</definition>
		<definition>demanding</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>enterprising</syn>
			<syn>spirited</syn>
			<syn>keen</syn>
			<syn>active</syn>
			<syn>daring</syn>
			<syn>eager</syn>
			<syn>intent</syn>
			<syn>enthusiastic</syn>
			<syn>hopeful</syn>
			<syn>striving</syn>
			<syn>vigorous</syn>
			<syn>aspiring</syn>
			<syn>energetic</syn>
			<syn>adventurous</syn>
			<syn>avid</syn>
			<syn>zealous</syn>
			<syn>intrepid</syn>
			<syn>resourceful</syn>
			<syn>purposeful</syn>
			<syn>desirous</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>demanding</syn>
			<syn>trying</syn>
			<syn>hard</syn>
			<syn>taxing</syn>
			<syn>difficult</syn>
			<syn>challenging</syn>
			<syn>tough</syn>
			<syn>severe</syn>
			<syn>impressive</syn>
			<syn>exhausting</syn>
			<syn>exacting</syn>
			<syn>bold</syn>
			<syn>elaborate</syn>
			<syn>formidable</syn>
			<syn>energetic</syn>
			<syn>strenuous</syn>
			<syn>pretentious</syn>
			<syn>arduous</syn>
			<syn>grandiose</syn>
			<syn>industrious</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>lazy</ant>
			<ant>apathetic</ant>
			<ant>unambitious</ant>
			<ant>good-for-nothing</ant>
			<ant></ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>easy</ant>
			<ant>simple</ant>
			<ant>modest</ant>
			<ant>unambitious</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>authority</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>authority</title>
		<eng-def>the official power to make decisions or to control other people</eng-def>
		<tr-def>yetki, otorite</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>a position of authority</ex>
			<ex>
				The investigators have the authority to examine all the company's records.
			</ex>
			<ex>We need the support of someone in authority.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>authority</title>
		<eng-def>
			an official group or government department with power to control particular public services
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>yasal, resmi yetkisi olan grup veya devlet dairesi</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>the local housing authority</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>authority</title>
		<eng-def>the quality of being confident and being able to control people</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bilirkiï¿½i, uzman, otorite</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She has an air of authority.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>an authority on sth</title>
		<eng-def>someone who has a lot of knowledge about a particular subject</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bir konuda uzman olan, yetkili, bilirkiï¿½i olan</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>She is an authority on seventeenth-century English literature.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Now he was exerting his authority in another way.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I didn't mean to sound like some kind of authority on the subject.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>"Get out," she said with as much authority as she could muster.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Still, what business could survive without a person with final authority on decisions?
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even then he had begun to distrust the authority of tradition and his teachers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He's unaccustomed to having his authority challenged.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			People that dictate the rules make decisions for others with much authority.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He had neither authority nor right to ignore her emphatic command that he leave her place and remain silent about what he'd seen.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It had to be difficult to maintain any semblance of authority with a toddler clinging to his face, but he managed to do it.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Anyone in authority seemed habitually out of the office after Dean gave his name.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Her father had been the final authority, but never had she questioned her mother's authority.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			News and information that undermine their credibility or authority aren't so welcome either.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is important to respect and submit to the authority to which you are assigned to.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			She had no authority to access anything and no ability to see the emerops facilities or fed facilities.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was thus practically a committee of the larger council, and assisted the king in his judicial work, its authority being as undefined as his own.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He had the authority to modify the documents for his benefit, but he decided not to abuse his power.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Had Giddon overstepped his authority?</sentence>
		<sentence>Andre at least had that authority.</sentence>
		<sentence>Someone has to be head of the household - final authority.</sentence>
		<sentence>Jackson rose and spoke with authority.</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>powers that be</definition>
		<definition>prerogative</definition>
		<definition>expert</definition>
		<definition>command</definition>
		<definition>permission</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>government</syn>
			<syn>police</syn>
			<syn>officials</syn>
			<syn>management</syn>
			<syn>administration</syn>
			<syn>Big Brother</syn>
			<syn>officialdom</syn>
			<syn>powers that be</syn>
			<syn>the state</syn>
			<syn>the system</syn>
			<syn>the Establishment</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>prerogative</syn>
			<syn>right</syn>
			<syn>influence</syn>
			<syn>might</syn>
			<syn>force</syn>
			<syn>power</syn>
			<syn>control</syn>
			<syn>charge</syn>
			<syn>rule</syn>
			<syn>government</syn>
			<syn>weight</syn>
			<syn>strength</syn>
			<syn>direction</syn>
			<syn>command</syn>
			<syn>licence</syn>
			<syn>privilege</syn>
			<syn>warrant</syn>
			<syn>say-so</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>domination</syn>
			<syn>jurisdiction</syn>
			<syn>supremacy</syn>
			<syn>dominion</syn>
			<syn>ascendancy</syn>
			<syn>mana</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>expert</syn>
			<syn>specialist</syn>
			<syn>professional</syn>
			<syn>master</syn>
			<syn>ace</syn>
			<syn>scholar</syn>
			<syn>guru</syn>
			<syn>buff</syn>
			<syn>wizard</syn>
			<syn>whizz</syn>
			<syn>virtuoso</syn>
			<syn>connoisseur</syn>
			<syn>boffin</syn>
			<syn>arbiter</syn>
			<syn>hotshot</syn>
			<syn>fundi</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>command</syn>
			<syn>power</syn>
			<syn>control</syn>
			<syn>rule</syn>
			<syn>management</syn>
			<syn>direction</syn>
			<syn>grasp</syn>
			<syn>sway</syn>
			<syn>domination</syn>
			<syn>mastery</syn>
			<syn>dominion</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>permission</syn>
			<syn>leave</syn>
			<syn>permit</syn>
			<syn>sanction</syn>
			<syn>licence</syn>
			<syn>approval</syn>
			<syn>go-ahead</syn>
			<syn>liberty</syn>
			<syn>consent</syn>
			<syn>warrant</syn>
			<syn>say-so</syn>
			<syn>tolerance</syn>
			<syn>justification</syn>
			<syn>green light</syn>
			<syn>assent</syn>
			<syn>authorization</syn>
			<syn>dispensation</syn>
			<syn>carte blanche</syn>
			<syn>sufferance</syn>
			<syn>a blank cheque</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>appoint</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>appoint</title>
		<eng-def>to officially choose someone for a job</eng-def>
		<tr-def>resmen atamak, gï¿½revlendirmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>He was appointed as company director last year.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>
			He was given the right to dispense justice, to coin money and to appoint the bishops in Bavaria.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This board has power to appoint a school director and a superintendent of instruction.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The school committee (who serve gratuitously) appoint the superintendent and supervisors of schools.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The president of the Republic, who is elected for four years by an electoral college, and cannot hold office for more than two successive terms, has a cabinet whose members he may appoint and remove freely, their number being determined by law.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He named one hundred preachers who after his death were to meet once a year, fill up vacancies in their number, appoint a president and secretary, station the preachers, admit proper persons into the ministry, and take general oversight of the societies.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was the general practice to appoint two or three to sit together (Van Espen, pars iii.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was further proposed to appoint one regiment of redif cavalry to each redif division.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But the achievements of the two civil agents were less noteworthy; and in 1905 it was agreed that, in view of the financial necessities of the provinces, the other great powers should each appoint delegates to a financial commission with extensive powers of control in fiscal matters.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The national executive appoints and removes the prefects of the departments and the sub-prefects of the provinces, and the prefects appoint the gobiernadores of the districts.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The sultan determined henceforth to appoint Greeks to the principalities as more likely to be subservient to his will than the natives hitherto appointed.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In 743, however, the mayors decided to appoint a king in the person of Childeric III., who was apparently connected with the Merovingian family.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The king; met them half way by inviting the majority to appoint a committee to settle the army question provisionally, and a committee was formed, which included Szell, Apponyi, Count Istvan Tisza.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Afterwards, Davis himself, as president of the Confederate states, was to appoint many volunteer officers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The bishop or, failing him, the metropolitan, was to see such legacies properly paid and applied and might appoint persons to administer the funds (Pollock and Maitland, op. cit.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Rumours of a reactionary plot by Austria and the Jesuits against Pius, induced him to create a national guard and to appoint Cardinal Ferretti as secretary of state.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			When he is an emperor, a king, or a president of a republic, it is not expected that he will act personally; he may appoint a delegate or delegates to act on his behalf, and avail himself of their labours and views, the ultimate decision being his only in name.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			wished to appoint him canon of Windsor, but the prime minister, Lord Liverpool, objected; Sumner received instead a royal chaplaincy and librarianship, and other preferments quickly followed, till in 1826 he was consecrated bishop of Llandaff and in 1827 bishop of Winchester.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			2 The narrative is of some value as it shows that while it was possible to appoint any one as a priest, since Micah, like David, appointed one of his own sons (xvii.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The exemption from the jurisdiction of the sheriff was recognized in England by the Sheriffs Act 1887, which provides that the sheriff of a county shall appoint a deputy at the expense of the lord of the liberty, such deputy to reside in or near the liberty.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			On the 15th of April they proposed that the parliament should appoint a provisional government and dissolve itself.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>assign</definition>
		<definition>decide</definition>
		<definition>equip</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>assign</syn>
			<syn>name</syn>
			<syn>choose</syn>
			<syn>commission</syn>
			<syn>select</syn>
			<syn>elect</syn>
			<syn>install</syn>
			<syn>delegate</syn>
			<syn>nominate</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>decide</syn>
			<syn>set</syn>
			<syn>choose</syn>
			<syn>establish</syn>
			<syn>determine</syn>
			<syn>settle</syn>
			<syn>fix</syn>
			<syn>arrange</syn>
			<syn>specify</syn>
			<syn>assign</syn>
			<syn>designate</syn>
			<syn>allot</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>equip</syn>
			<syn>provide</syn>
			<syn>supply</syn>
			<syn>furnish</syn>
			<syn>fit out</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>fire</ant>
			<ant>dismiss</ant>
			<ant>sack</ant>
			<ant>give the sack</ant>
			<ant>give (someone) their P45</ant>
			<ant>give (someone) their pink slip</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>cancel</ant>
		</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>strip</ant>
			<ant>dismantle</ant>
			<ant>divest</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>ambiguity</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>ambiguity</title>
		<eng-def>the state of having more than one possible meaning</eng-def>
		<tr-def>anlam kargaï¿½asï¿½, ï¿½ok anlamlï¿½lï¿½k, karmaï¿½a, anlaï¿½ï¿½lmazlï¿½k</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>Legal documents must be free of ambiguity.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Their actions showed moral ambiguity.</sentence>
		<sentence>The ambiguity begins to disappear as more explanations are made.</sentence>
		<sentence>She chose her clothing carefully to avoid gender ambiguity.</sentence>
		<sentence>This statement has a lot of ambiguity.</sentence>
		<sentence>The ambiguity cannot be cured.</sentence>
		<sentence>They found possible ambiguity in interpretation.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This should clarify any ambiguity regarding the practices undertaken.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He is in charge of ambiguity resolution.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Where the words are not clear, other factors can be taken into account to resolve the ambiguity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Speakers of English were asked to judge the ambiguity of the grammar.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There were come cases of ambiguity in the definition and there have been wide variations in practice.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>The ambiguity lies in the multifold purpose of the activities.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The ambiguity of his language makes many interpretations possible.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>On the other hand, the ambiguity may be quite unintentional.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			What ambiguity they possess arises from the ambiguity of morality itself.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Great ambiguity is the natural result of this procedure.</sentence>
		<sentence>(2) Ambiguity.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The ambiguity in his criterion, however, seems entirely to have escaped Hume's attention.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			There is no ambiguity in calling conditionals with true antecedents "true" or "false."
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The main girder is then virtually a continuous girder hinged at the points of contrary flexure, so that no ambiguity can arise as to the stresses.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>vagueness</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>vagueness</syn>
			<syn>doubt</syn>
			<syn>puzzle</syn>
			<syn>uncertainty</syn>
			<syn>obscurity</syn>
			<syn>enigma</syn>
			<syn>equivocation</syn>
			<syn>inconclusiveness</syn>
			<syn>dubiety</syn>
			<syn>doubtfulness</syn>
			<syn>indefiniteness</syn>
			<syn>dubiousness</syn>
			<syn>tergiversation</syn>
			<syn>indeterminateness</syn>
			<syn>equivocality</syn>
			<syn>equivocacy</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>






























</main>