<main>
<word>
	<name>grind</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>grind</title>
		<eng-def>
			to keep rubbing something between two rough, hard surfaces until it becomes a powder
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>öðütmek, unufak etmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>to grind coffee</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>grind</title>
		<eng-def>to rub a blade against a hard surface to make it sharp</eng-def>
		<tr-def>bilemek, keskinleþtirmek</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>grind your teeth</title>
		<eng-def>to rub your teeth together, making an unpleasant sound</eng-def>
		<tr-def>diþlerini gýcýrdatmak, gýcýrtý sesi çýkarmak</tr-def>
		<examples/>
	</div>
	<div>
		<title>grind</title>
		<eng-def>
			work or effort that is boring and unpleasant and makes you tired because it does not change
		</eng-def>
		<tr-def>beyhude çaba/çalýþma; sýkýcý ve zor iþ, ömür törpüsü</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>the daily grind</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>She thought she heard him grind his teeth and frowned.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			They allowed us to grind the spices, pick over the raisins and lick the stirring spoons.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>They crush or grind the food, and are hence called " molars."</sentence>
		<sentence>
			paddle the canoe and fish, while the girls learn to spin and weave, grind maize, and cook - good conduct being enforced by punishments of increasing severity, up to pricking their bodies with aloethorns and holding their faces over burning chillies.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The island of Griend (or Grind) once boasted a walled town, which was destroyed by flood at the end of the 13th century.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			grind, gate), forming the boundary between the parishes of: Northmavine and belting, is only 60 yds.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The Grind of the Navir ("Gate of the Giants") is a staircase carved by the waves out of the porphyry cliffs.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In this "mill," as he calls it, Erasmus continued to grind incessantly for eight years.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			mola, a mill, molere, to grind; from the same root, mol, is derived " meal;" the word appears in other Teutonic languages, cf.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			i AEUpLr1]S, pertaining to icXevpov, ground meal, from aViv, to grind), a genus of trees belonging to the natural order Euphorbiaceae.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The permanent residents are generally limited to the major-domo and his family; and in the dry season labourers are hired, of any colour that can be obtained - some from the low country, others from the highlands - for three, four, or five months, who gather in and grind the cane, and plant for the harvest of the following year; but the staff of resident Indian labourers, such as exists in the farms of the sierra, cannot be kept up in the Yungas, as these half-warm valleys are called.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			molde, from a Teutonic root meaning to grind, reduce to powder, cf.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He found himself looked upon with curiosity as a precocious phenomenon, a "made man," an intellectual machine set to grind certain tunes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Bars of copper drawn over the bottom by mules or water-power (like the stone drags in the arrastra) grind off fine particles of copper, which hasten the reduction of the silver and diminish the formation of calomel.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The parish of Walls, in the west, is said to contain more voes, whence its name (an erroneous rendering of the Norse waas), than all the rest of Shetland; while the neck of land at Mavis Grind (Norse, maev, narrow; eid, isthmus;.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Gabbro occurs in the peninsula of Fethland; diorite in Northmavine between Rinas Voe and Mavis Grind; and epidote-syenite in Dunrossness.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Verse 13: " Nobles endured to grind, And princes staggered under logs " (a'nrn for o'nn:, which belongs to verse 14; a'nru for a'nya.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			XLOos, stone, Tpi(3Ety, to rub, grind down) are drugs given to prevent the formation of urinary calculi.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>Use a coffee grinder to grind the star anise to a powder.</sentence>
		<sentence>nine-to-five daily grind?</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>crush</definition>
		<definition>press</definition>
		<definition>grate</definition>
		<definition>sharpen</definition>
		<definition>hard work</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>crush</syn>
			<syn>mill</syn>
			<syn>powder</syn>
			<syn>grate</syn>
			<syn>pulverize</syn>
			<syn>pound</syn>
			<syn>kibble</syn>
			<syn>abrade</syn>
			<syn>granulate</syn>
			<syn>comminute</syn>
			<syn>triturate</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>press</syn>
			<syn>push</syn>
			<syn>crush</syn>
			<syn>jam</syn>
			<syn>mash</syn>
			<syn>force down</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>grate</syn>
			<syn>scrape</syn>
			<syn>grit</syn>
			<syn>gnash</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>sharpen</syn>
			<syn>file</syn>
			<syn>polish</syn>
			<syn>sand</syn>
			<syn>smooth</syn>
			<syn>whet</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>hard work</syn>
			<syn>labour</syn>
			<syn>effort</syn>
			<syn>task</syn>
			<syn>sweat</syn>
			<syn>chore</syn>
			<syn>toil</syn>
			<syn>drudgery</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>identical</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>identical</title>
		<eng-def>exactly the same</eng-def>
		<tr-def>týpatýp ayný, benzer, týpký</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>The two rooms were almost/virtually identical.</ex>
			<ex>She found a dress identical to the one in the picture.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>"They're not identical twins," he answered.</sentence>
		<sentence>The chromatin is practically identical with nuclein.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He crossed his arms as he approached the woman who was identical to his mate.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>He was dressed in a suit identical to the one Alex wore.</sentence>
		<sentence>The distance seems to be identical by either route.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Gabriel's ex-lover was identical to her in every way, even garbed in the same dress.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			And again all the faces in that crowd bore an identical expression, though now it was certainly not an expression of curiosity or gratitude, but of angry resolve.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			I took the ring you gave me and I too scratched that identical message on my bedroom window, the very same room where you and I have stolen our few hours together.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			On account of this difficulty, the atomic weights published by Dalton, and the more accurate ones of Berzelius, were not always identical with the values now accepted, but were often simple multiples or submultiples of these.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			"This is for the underworld, and this you will know when to use," Darkyn said. He handed the shapeshifter a pouch identical to the one he'd given the other shapeshifting demon and a small talisman on a chain.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Gabe leaned across her to grab the bag with his weapons' polishing supplies. A necklace with two emeralds – identical to the one he'd given her to wear – dangled above her.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Public interest centred for some years round the allegation that he lived a double life and was identical with Mr T.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Wiry and lean, Darian's golden gaze was identical to that of his brother, the White God.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Ah, they don't see it! came identical shouts from the ranks all along the regiment.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He lifted the chain, kiri's chain, and looked at the identical marks, struck by the idea that he somehow belonged to the same world they did.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This contradiction arises from the fact that military science assumes the strength of an army to be identical with its numbers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Josephus suggests, and Jerome, apparently following him, affirms, that the name is identical with that of the Ishmaelite tribe of Nebaioth (Gen.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Even identical twins, thought until recently to have identical DNA, actually have slightly different DNA.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			until he was certain the river was identical with that reported by Sturt as joining the Murray about 142° E.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Dressed all in black with weapons strapped in places identical to where Gabriel wore his, the tall man was lean with cold eyes.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>alike</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>alike</syn>
			<syn>like</syn>
			<syn>matching</syn>
			<syn>equal</syn>
			<syn>twin</syn>
			<syn>equivalent</syn>
			<syn>corresponding</syn>
			<syn>duplicate</syn>
			<syn>synonymous</syn>
			<syn>indistinguishable</syn>
			<syn>analogous</syn>
			<syn>interchangeable</syn>
			<syn>a dead ringer</syn>
			<syn>the dead spit</syn>
			<syn>the same</syn>
			<syn>like two peas in a pod</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>different</ant>
			<ant>unlike</ant>
			<ant>distinct</ant>
			<ant>diverse</ant>
			<ant>disparate</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>isolate</name>
	<star>false</star>
	<div>
		<title>isolate</title>
		<eng-def>to separate someone or something from other people or things</eng-def>
		<tr-def>ayýrmak, ayrý tutmak, tecrit etmek</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				Scientists have been able to isolate the gene responsible for causing the illness.
			</ex>
			<ex>He had been isolated from other prisoners.</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>All she did was isolate the children and Alex.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Dean tried to isolate the sound, looking frantically in all downward directions, trying to see a trace, a telltale puff of smoke in the gathering dusk.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Priestley in 1772 was the first to isolate it in the gaseous condition, and Sir H.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The metal is difficult to isolate, and until recently it may be doubted whether the pure metal had been obtained.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It is impossible to isolate a child in the midst of society, so that he shall not be influenced by the beliefs of those with whom he associates.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The lines of cardinal importance are (I) the rasceta or cross sulci, which isolate the hand from the forearm at the wrist, and which are the flexion folds between the looser forearm skin and that tied down to the fascia above the level of the anterior annular ligament.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			of France, but after declaring war on France in August 1294 he did nothing to assist his ally~ At home he relieved the cities of some of their burdens and upheld them in the quarrel about the Pfahlburger; and he sought to isolate Albert of Habsburg, who was treating with Philip of France.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			This was preceded, on the 25th of April, by an attack, headed by Cochrane, on the Turkish troops established near the monastery of St Spiridion, the result of which was to establish communications between the Greeks at Munychia and Phalerum and isolate Reshid's vanguard on the promontory of the Piraeus.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His attempts to isolate a glycolytic ferment from flesh were also only partially successful.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Second, I can duplicate the DNA with some time in my lab and isolate the antigen, meaning I can make someone immune to our enemies' powers.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Largely upon the representations of Howe, Burgoyne and others, it was determined to shift the field from Boston to New York city, from there to hold the line of the Hudson river in co-operation with a force to move down from Canada under Carleton and Burgoyne, and thus effectually to isolate New England.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Mention should also be made of a third method which has hardly yet been tried, namely, that of endeavouring to isolate one of the three "directions" by the method of suggestion or even hypnotic trance observations.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Although unable to isolate the metal, he recognized its analogy to sodium and potassium; this was confirmed by R.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Its further cooling undergoes three spontaneous retardations, one at K' (Ar 3 about 820°), at which part of the iron begins to isolate itself within the austenite mother-metal in the form of envelopes of 0-ferrite, i.e.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The best method of obtaining a strong beam of polarized light is to isolate one of the streams into which a beam of common light is resolved by double refraction.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Enclosing the photosphere is a truly gaseous envelope which is called the chromosphere, and which shows a spectrum of bright lines when we can isolate its emission from that of the photosphere.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The suspicions as to the stability of the Triple Alliance ~ produced, indeed, for some years a kind of nervous ness in the attitude of the government, whose deter mination to assert for Germany a leading international role tended to isolate her in Europe.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In order to isolate the anhydrous diazonium salts, the method of E.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			It was his purpose to show that the forms of thought (which he sought to isolate from the peculiarities incident to the organic body) were not merely customary means for licking into convenient shape the data of perception, but entered as underlying elements into the constitution of objects, making experience possible and determining the fundamental structure of nature.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Not only so, but the physician, thus fascinated by "types," and impressed by the silent monumentsof the pathological museum, was led to localize disease too much, to isolate the acts of nature, and to forget not only the continuity of the phases which lead up to the exemplary forms, or link them together, but to forget also that even between the types themselves relations of affinity must exist - and these oftentimes none the less intimate for apparent diversities of form, for types of widely different form may be, and indeed often are, more closely allied than types which have more superficial resemblance - and to forget, moreover, how largely negative is the process of abstraction by which types are imagined.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>separate</definition>
		<definition>quarantine</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>separate</syn>
			<syn>break up</syn>
			<syn>cut off</syn>
			<syn>detach</syn>
			<syn>split up</syn>
			<syn>insulate</syn>
			<syn>segregate</syn>
			<syn>disconnect</syn>
			<syn>divorce</syn>
			<syn>sequester</syn>
			<syn>set apart</syn>
			<syn>disunite</syn>
			<syn>estrange</syn>
		</synonymPack>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>quarantine</syn>
			<syn>separate</syn>
			<syn>exclude</syn>
			<syn>cut off</syn>
			<syn>detach</syn>
			<syn>keep in solitude</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
		<antonymPack>null</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>

<word>
	<name>inordinate</name>
	<star>true</star>
	<div>
		<title>inordinate</title>
		<eng-def>much more than is usual or suitable</eng-def>
		<tr-def>aþýrý, haddinden fazla, gereðinden çok</tr-def>
		<examples>
			<ex>
				James seems to spend an inordinate amount of time on his computer.
			</ex>
		</examples>
	</div>
	<sentences>
		<sentence>Am I not a detective with inordinate skills?</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Maximilian was also a writer of books, and his writings display his inordinate vanity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the Upper House he was the spokesman of the gentry against the magnates, whose inordinate privileges he would have curtailed or abolished.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			In the negotiations for peace the inordinate pretensions of the Muscovite prince were put forward boldly: he not only refused to restore Smolensk, but claimed Kiev and a number of other towns on the ground that in the old time of the independent principalities they had belonged to descendants of Rurik.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>- ix.) is again inordinate in length, and it stands alone.</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The two points thus meeting, the bill is 1 This peculiarity is found as an accidental malformation in the crows (Corvidae) and other groups; it is comparable to the monstrosities seen in rabbits and other members of the order Glires, in which the incisor teeth grow to an inordinate length.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			He was undoubtedly an extremely able soldier and a skilful statesman, and much of his legislation shows a real political sense; but his inordinate ambition, his oppressive methods of government and taxation, and his cruelty created enemies on all sides, and led to the collapse of the edifice of dominion which he had raised.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			over his son was, indeed, far greater than is commonly supposed, and it accounts for much in Charles XII.'s character which is otherwise inexplicable, for instance his precocious reserve and taciturnity, his dislike of everything French, and his inordinate contempt for purely diplomatic methods.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Nevertheless, the influence of Donna Olimpia was baneful; and she made herself thoroughly detested for her inordinate ambition and rapacity.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			But it was found that there were no funds in the treasury to satisfy their inordinate demands, and they were obliged to be contented with one-half the stipulated sums, which, after many difficulties, were paid in specie and in jewels, with the exception of 584,905 rupees.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The conditions of peace were naturally humiliating for Valdemar,' though, ultimately, he contrived to render illusory many of the inordinate privileges he was obliged to concede.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			They are deeply separated by religious differences, and their mutual jealousies, their inordinate vanity, English Miles 0 5 io 20 30 40 50 Railways Capitals of Vilayets &c. C Longitude East 42 of Greenwich their versatility and their cosmopolitan character must always be an obstacle to the realization of the dreams of the nationalists.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Then at the end of the moral virtues justice is treated at inordinate length, and in a different manner from the others, which are regarded as means between two vices, whereas justice appears as a mean only because it is of the middle between too much and too little.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			The indiscriminate use of Mercator's projection, for maps of the world, is to be deprecated owing to the inordinate exaggeration of areas in high latitudes.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			His unwearied activity and inordinate vanity led him to undertake a great many costly public works, many of them, such as the erection of palaces and churches, unremunerative.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			These ordinances proved, however, generally ineffectual to secure strictness of diet, and contemporaneous literature abounds with satirical remarks and complaints concerning the inordinate extravagance of the tables of the abbots.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Circumstances which strike his fancy, or furnish convenient texts for his polemic, are handled at inordinate length, while others are rapidly dismissed or passed over altogether.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			For the clergy as a whole, in spite of his criticism of individuals, he has the very highest respect, as also for the monks, without himself making any inordinate religious professions.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			Thus despite an inordinate love of adventure, which makes him appear rather a wandering chieftain than an established ruler, he was essentially a man of insight and progress.
		</sentence>
		<sentence>
			the latter part of his reign, and also the inordinate squandering of money, the autos-da-f in the provinces and in Paris, the harsh repression of reform and free thought, and the sale of justice; while the nation became impoverished and the state was at the mercy of the caprices of royal mistressesall of which was to become more and more pronounced during the twelve years of Henry IIs government.
		</sentence>
	</sentences>
	<definitions>
		<definition>excessive</definition>
	</definitions>
	<synonyms>
		<synonymPack>
			<syn>excessive</syn>
			<syn>unreasonable</syn>
			<syn>disproportionate</syn>
			<syn>extravagant</syn>
			<syn>undue</syn>
			<syn>preposterous</syn>
			<syn>unwarranted</syn>
			<syn>exorbitant</syn>
			<syn>unrestrained</syn>
			<syn>intemperate</syn>
			<syn>unconscionable</syn>
			<syn>immoderate</syn>
		</synonymPack>
	</synonyms>
	<antonyms>
		<antonymPack>
			<ant>reasonable</ant>
			<ant>sensible</ant>
			<ant>restrained</ant>
			<ant>inhibited</ant>
			<ant>rightful</ant>
			<ant>temperate</ant>
		</antonymPack>
	</antonyms>
</word>






</main>